中文字幕
This is CS50 and this is lecture 6.
And you'll recall that last week we introduced web programming
中文字幕
by way of HTML and CSS, or at least the building blocks
because we don't actually have the ability to program yet.
中文字幕
It's just markup, HTML and CSS with stylization thereof.
But we introduced this metaphor last week of a protocol called TCP/IP.
中文字幕
And we related it to, of course, an envelope.
And on this envelope, virtually, on the front
中文字幕
was at least two pieces of information.
And if anyone remembers what were those two
中文字幕
pieces of information in the to field?
Someone else who we didn't hear from recently?
中文字幕
Yeah?
An IP address.
中文字幕
Yeah.
An IP address, a numeric address that uniquely identifies your computer
中文字幕
and someone else's computer.
And one other thing, if you remember.
中文字幕
Oh, come on.
It was like two minutes ago.
中文字幕
OK.
Yeah.
中文字幕
A port number.
So another number, shorter number, that's just a number like 80 or 443
中文字幕
referring to HTTP or HTTPS, or other numbers,
like 25 for email and the like.
中文字幕
And so together these unique addresses allow you to send information
to not only a specific computer, but a specific service
中文字幕
running on that computer.
And in order to actually request information from that server,
中文字幕
there's this other protocol called HTTP, Hypertext Transfer Protocol.
This is what's inside of the envelope.
中文字幕
So when the server opens it up, metaphorically,
looks inside, this is the command that that server reads in order to decide
中文字幕
what it should actually respond with.
And so this request here is telling the server--
中文字幕
otherwise known as www.example.com in this particular example--
to send back what exactly in its own envelope to me
中文字幕
and my laptop if I were to request this?
A specific web page.
中文字幕
And someone else, which web page specifically, presumably?
Index.
中文字幕
Yeah, so index.html, which we said last week
just tends to be the default file name on a server for a web page
中文字幕
that's just selected by default. And it doesn't have to be called this,
but it's a human convention.
中文字幕
And the rest of this is just a verb saying, literally, get me that file.
This is just telling the server what version of HTTP
中文字幕
I speak so that humans can improve it and upgrade it over time.
But this would tell the server to return index.html.
中文字幕
Meanwhile, we saw more sophisticated get queries
when we started talking about Google, and any website that
中文字幕
has not just a front end, like HTML and CSS, but also a back end.
And a back end is where the logic is, where the server is,
中文字幕
and the interesting work, ultimately.
And so this slash search indicates some kind
中文字幕
of software running on Google servers as of last week
that's simply responds to requests.
中文字幕
And what did question mark q equals cats do or represent in that demonstration?
User input.
中文字幕
Yeah, user input.
So the question mark just says, that's it for the file name or the URL.
中文字幕
Here comes the user's input.
Q is just literally the HTTP parameter or input
中文字幕
that Larry and Sergey, founders of Google,
20 years ago decided would represent the user's input, q for query.
中文字幕
Equal just means that query that the human typed in was cats.
But the human doesn't even have to type this in.
中文字幕
Once you understand HTTP, if you really wanted to be kind of a nerd,
you could go to www.google.com/search?q=cats and it
中文字幕
would induce the search for you because at the end of the day,
that's all the browser is doing.
中文字幕
When you have these web forms that you now have the ability to create,
it's just automating the process of generating these HTTP messages.
中文字幕
Now, the server hopefully responds with a message you never, ever actually see,
HTTP 200, which literally means OK.
中文字幕
Of course, many of us have seen numbers other than 200 appear, like what?
404, which means?
中文字幕
File not found.
Now, why the humans decided years ago to tell
中文字幕
other humans what that numeric code is, I mean,
that is an uninteresting detail.
中文字幕
But the world, for whatever reason, has revealed in many web sites 404.
But it just means the same thing.
中文字幕
Everything is not OK.
A file was not found.
中文字幕
You might see something else like this.
We saw this with Harvard, in fact, curiously,
中文字幕
that Harvard had moved permanently.
Now, Harvard was responding to certain queries with HTTP 301s
中文字幕
in order to achieve what feature or effect?
Why?
中文字幕
Yeah.
Redirections.
中文字幕
So this is kind of a low-level way of describing it.
But 301, even though it says moved permanently,
中文字幕
that's a more technical hint to the browser saying,
Harvard moved not to whatever URL you just came from,
中文字幕
but to this URL specifically.
And now Harvard was probably, if you recall, redirecting me from what URL?
中文字幕
If I wasn't already at that URL, where might I have been?
Maybe dot com, if they actually own multiple domains and were redirecting.
中文字幕
That could work.
What else?
中文字幕
Yeah.
Just HTTP.
中文字幕
Yeah.
Maybe I just typed in HTTP, and Harvard, in the interest of security,
中文字幕
wants to force my browser to request this page again via HTTPS.
Sometimes a website might prepend the www if you haven't typed it in,
中文字幕
or you can be redirected most anywhere.
In fact, if you go to CS50's own website by just typing CS50.harvard.edu,
中文字幕
watch the URL.
You'll be redirected to a more specific page, depending on the time of year.
中文字幕
So we use these tricks, as well.
404 not found might look like this, but inside deeper
中文字幕
of that metaphorical envelope is the actual contents of the web page.
So you get back not only these HTTP headers,
中文字幕
as they're called, in the top of the response, so to speak,
but you also get back HTML, yet another language we looked at,
中文字幕
this one actually a language, but not a programming language.
These tags tell the browser exactly what to do and to render.
中文字幕
We introduced this style tag, though.
What did that allow us to do that HTML alone did not?
中文字幕
Yeah.
Use CSS to beautify the site and just make it nicer.
中文字幕
HTML, for the most part, is about structure
and about tagging the contents of your web page in a way
中文字幕
that the browser finds helpful.
But CSS is really for the user's benefit, at the end of the day,
中文字幕
and his or her eyes, because it really lets
you control font size and positioning and lower-level stuff
中文字幕
that you might have started tinkering with with the most recent problem set.
Now, we'd proposed that you probably shouldn't just
中文字幕
start typing CSS inside of your HTML page
because it's just a little harder to maintain as your examples get
中文字幕
more sophisticated.
So you might factor it out.
中文字幕
And odds are you did this for the problem
set because when making a home page, if you have the same CSS
中文字幕
styles across multiple files, it would be pretty silly and inefficient to copy
and paste them again and again when you can factor them out like this.
中文字幕
Lastly, we looked at JavaScript, last time,
another programming language that's super similar
中文字幕
to see, at least at first glance.
But it actually gets rid of a lot of the lower level
中文字幕
headaches like pointers and memory addresses and that
that we've struggled with in recent weeks.
中文字幕
But most important was how we used it.
So you can consider a web page like this as once it's loaded by your browser
中文字幕
as just being a tree structure.
Thinking back a couple of weeks to our discussion of data structures
中文字幕
and each of these nodes in the tree we saw in JavaScript can be manipulated.
And via that very simple principle, writing
中文字幕
code that modifies this existing tree in the browser's memory,
means you can make much more dynamic things like Gmail and Facebook
中文字幕
and any number of websites that are constantly changing.
You did not do this yet for the problems set.
中文字幕
You made static web pages just by hard coding HTML and CSS.
But starting next week, once we have, thanks to this week, the vocabulary
中文字幕
of Python will you start to make things more dynamic
and then even bring back into play JavaScript,
中文字幕
bringing all of these various threads together.
And to include the JavaScript, recall, we used either a script tag at the top
中文字幕
or refactored it out to a file.
Or in some cases, it's necessary or beneficial
中文字幕
to move it down to the bottom of the file or factor it out like that,
but more on that down the road.
中文字幕
So any questions on last week or on HTTP, HTML, CSS, or TCP/IP?
No?
中文字幕
Anything at all?
Oh, yeah?
中文字幕
So in what case would you put the script
tag up at the top
中文字幕
Good question.
So in what cases would you put the script tag up at the top
中文字幕
versus at the bottom?
If the code you're writing in JavaScript manipulates
中文字幕
the DOM, the tree that I had on the screen just a moment ago,
the catch is that that tree needs to exist when your code is executed.
中文字幕
So if you, for instance, have JavaScript code up here in the head of your page,
but the nodes in the tree, the tags that you
中文字幕
want to manipulate in changing things to red to green to blue
like we did last week, or making things blank, are down here in the page,
中文字幕
you can't write your code up here and have it change things in the page
down here because it's happening out of order.
中文字幕
So similar in spirit to C where things have to happen in the right order,
if you want to change something down here,
中文字幕
your code needs to at least be down here,
or you need to use some fancier techniques to say,
中文字幕
I'm going to write my code up here but wait a few seconds
before executing it until the whole webpage is loaded.
中文字幕
So for most of the examples we looked at, this was not an issue.
But we'll come back to this perhaps before long.
中文字幕
All right, so let's now take the same approach
that we did last time of introducing one language by way of another.
中文字幕
You'll recall, of course, that we started the whole semester with Scratch
and then we transitioned a few weeks back now to C. Last week
中文字幕
we made some comparisons with JavaScript.
Let's do the same thing briefly with Python
中文字幕
but then spend more time at the keyboard comparing the two to see
what actually is different about these.
中文字幕
So why in another language, though, first?
We have Scratch, C, JavaScript, Python, not to mention HTML and CSS
中文字幕
for different purposes.
Like, why do we have all of these darn languages already?
中文字幕
Why didn't humans just decide, that's it, we're all using Scratch?
We're all using C or JavaScript or Python?
中文字幕
What's, perhaps, the intuition behind that?
Why are there so many damn languages, not to mention in this one course?
中文字幕
Yeah?
Say once more?
中文字幕
Different ones are good for different things.
Yeah, different ones are good for different things.
中文字幕
And this probably goes without saying for something like Scratch, right?
It's so visual.
中文字幕
It's so graphical and animated.
It makes sense that the puzzle pieces--
中文字幕
or that the language itself is based on puzzle pieces
and dragging and dropping.
中文字幕
So maybe languages are tailored to certain applications.
But is that true for C, Python, and JavaScript, which
中文字幕
are all text-based languages we'll see?
for example, they're
中文字幕
different levels of abstraction.
OK.
中文字幕
Different levels of abstraction.
C is very  actually dealing with a lot of things that you
中文字幕
don't have to think about in Python--
Good.
中文字幕
--where these sort of things are taken care of for you,
such as memory allocations and so on.
中文字幕
And so depending on what level of abstraction you want to work on
and what parts you want to manipulate.
中文字幕
OK, good.
Bringing it back to abstraction does make sense.
中文字幕
C is, indeed, very low level, literally having the ability to manipulate memory
and via pointers and so forth.
中文字幕
And that's great because you can do anything you want with the computer.
But it comes at great risk and great cost.
中文字幕
One, the cost is human time.
It's just painful to write that kind of code sometimes.
中文字幕
Two, it's also very risky because if you make a mistake, even a simple mistake,
the whole computer can crash.
中文字幕
And we didn't see examples of this, but you
can make your code vulnerable to a hacker
中文字幕
if he or she is able to somehow exploit a memory-related bug
and read all of the passwords in your program, or something like that.
中文字幕
So with great power comes great responsibility
is kind of the mantra of C down here.
中文字幕
But JavaScript we saw allows us to do things a little more high-level.
There were no pointers.
中文字幕
There was no memory.
We didn't talk about things at that level.
中文字幕
We talked about things at the level of a tree,
a DOM in memory and changing colors and positioning of things on the screen.
中文字幕
And that's, indeed, a higher level.
Now, Python is not necessarily even web-centric.
中文字幕
It's more of a multi-purpose language.
People use Python to write command-line programs,
中文字幕
like we will soon, at the keyboard, like we've been doing with C.
You can also, though, use it, as we'll see
中文字幕
next week, to generate other languages.
So next week we will write code in Python,
中文字幕
the language we're about to see, to generate another language, HTML
and CSS.
中文字幕
Some of you probably noticed in your homepages that you had some redundancy.
You probably had similar tags or similar structure,
中文字幕
maybe a similar menu across pages.
Python and other languages will let us factor that
中文字幕
out and generate those commonalities a lot more
easily, among many other things.
中文字幕
And it's also arguably easier and faster to write
because it comes with so many more features, as we will soon see.
中文字幕
So in fact-- you know what?
Let me do this.
中文字幕
Let me go ahead and open up CS50 IDE.
Let me go ahead and create a new file.
中文字幕
And out of curiosity, of our recent problem
sets, what was maybe among the most challenging programs you've written?
中文字幕
Crack.
OK, crack was a good one.
中文字幕
What else?
Resize.
中文字幕
Resize, recover.
Yeah, definitely the forensics ones.
中文字幕
And more people probably did recover and resize.
So let's take resize, for example.
中文字幕
So let me go ahead and write a program in a file called resize.py for Python,
instead of .c, and see if we can't spend, what, few hours, couple days,
中文字幕
as you probably did in C, implementing resize.
Well, let me go ahead and do this.
中文字幕
I'm going to go ahead and--
let's see.
中文字幕
First I'm going to import some features that just come with Python.
And I'm going to go ahead and say from sys import argv.
中文字幕
And I'm going to go ahead and also do from pil import image.
Don't know yet what these are.
中文字幕
We'll tease this apart in a moment.
But then let me just do a check.
中文字幕
If the length of--
rather, if the length of argv does not equal 4,
中文字幕
I'm going to go ahead and exit for the user and say the usage of this program
is Python resize.py and in file, out file.
中文字幕
So even though some of this should look cryptic at the moment,
there's some commonalities-- argv, you recall, from C,
中文字幕
and this usage string that we printed out whenever anything went wrong.
That looks very similar in spirit to C.
中文字幕
And what did we do in resize?
If you implemented resize, like the less comfy version,
中文字幕
to increase the size of things, you probably declared a variable like an
and got sys--
中文字幕
or rather, argv bracket one to get access to it.
I'm going to go ahead and convert that or cast that to an int.
中文字幕
You probably had an infile variable that gave you access to argv two.
You probably had an out file variable that gave you access to argv three,
中文字幕
and so forth.
And it turns out in Python, you know what?
中文字幕
I can actually use a library, code that other people have written.
Let me come up with a variable called in image, like infile.
中文字幕
This is my input image.
And that's going to equal image.open because I
中文字幕
want to open this thing called infile.
And then the width--
中文字幕
let me get the width and the height of the existing image
by doing input image.size.
中文字幕
And then let me go ahead and make a new image-- out image, I'll call it--
which is going to equal the input image calling a resize function
中文字幕
and doing the width times n, which is the number the human probably typed in,
and height times n, which is the number the human typed in.
中文字幕
Then let me go ahead and just save the outfile as follows.
Outfile, OK.
中文字幕
Done.
Problem set three.
中文字幕
Tada.
OK, either really exciting or really, really disheartening perhaps.
中文字幕
So with the right language, as you say, can you
solve problems so much more easily.
中文字幕
Now, I'm being a little disingenuous because I'm also
leveraging what's called a library.
中文字幕
And we had access to these in C. And undoubtedly
we could have dug a little deeper on the internet
中文字幕
into other people's available code and found maybe a library for bitmap files.
But notice that there is no dealing with padding now.
中文字幕
There's no dealing with arrays.
There's no dealing with memory because I'm using the right tool for the job.
中文字幕
And if I wrote this code correctly-- and let
me cross my fingers that I didn't make any typos.
中文字幕
Let me go ahead here and get myself a copy
of smiley, which I brought with me.
中文字幕
So that was the tiny little image from last week.
Let me go ahead and open this in the IDE.
中文字幕
Smiley, super small.
Just a few pixels there.
中文字幕
And let me go ahead now and run Python, which we'll see why in a moment,
resize.
中文字幕
Let's increase this by a factor of 10, increasing Smiley, and call it out.bmp.
Now let me go ahead and open out.bnp and voila, it indeed seems to work.
中文字幕
Right, no funky colors.
No weird sizes.
中文字幕
No padding.
No padding of all things.
中文字幕
It's just now Python.
So you can probably glean some of the logic that's going on here.
中文字幕
But some of it certainly should and probably does look magical.
So let's use today to tease this apart and appreciate not only
中文字幕
what you can do with another language like Python,
but how it's similar and different and how it actually
中文字幕
is built upon something like C. So let's do some comparisons first
so that we can see that it's not a huge stretch to introduce
中文字幕
yet another language so quickly.
So recall that in Scratch if we wanted to set a variable, like counter,
中文字幕
to zero, you might simply do something like this,
setting it equal to zero at left.
中文字幕
In C, we would do the same thing here at the right.
In JavaScript, this instead looked a little different.
中文字幕
What did we do in JavaScript?
Yeah, we used let instead because we don't specify explicitly the type.
中文字幕
But we do need to tell the computer, let me have this variable called counter.
In Python, it's going to be that.
中文字幕
So we've gotten rid of the type still.
We've gotten rid of any mention of let or another keyword.
中文字幕
And we've gotten rid of-- perhaps most gratifyingly--
semi-colons are gone.
中文字幕
No more semi-colons.
And no more curly braces in the way you've seen them thus far.
中文字幕
So that was C, JavaScript, and now Python.
So how about something like this?
中文字幕
In Scratch, if you wanted to increment a counter by one,
you would use a block like this.
中文字幕
In C, we would do the same on the right here in code.
In JavaScript, did it look any different on the right?
中文字幕
No.
You haven't had occasion to use this yet.
中文字幕
But one of the sort of revelations of JavaScript was that's also JavaScript.
It was identical.
中文字幕
Something like this, though, is Python.
So it's almost the same.
中文字幕
But I've gotten rid of the semi-colon.
But the logic is exactly the same--
中文字幕
set counter on the left equal to whatever it is on the right plus one
additional value.
中文字幕
What about this?
This in C had what effect?
中文字幕
Incrementing the variable.
So this is exactly the same.
中文字幕
It's sort of a nice shorthand notation for doing counter equals
counter plus 1, which just gets a little tedious to type.
中文字幕
We had that same syntax in JavaScript.
And you can probably guess in Python, what's it going to look like?
中文字幕
Same thing without the--
Same thing minus the semi-colon.
中文字幕
So pretty nice pattern so far.
Languages just keep getting trimmer and trimmer, if you will.
中文字幕
In C, recall that we could just do plus plus,
which was another trick for automating that same process.
中文字幕
JavaScript allows for the same.
And if you really like this syntax, I can't show you a slide for Python.
中文字幕
Doesn't exist.
Can no longer do plus plus.
中文字幕
So we're paying a price.
The author of Python did not include this in the language.
中文字幕
But that's OK.
We at least have this one, which is not too horrible.
中文字幕
So what else did we look at last time?
An if condition like this, comparing if x is less than y,
中文字幕
in C it looks like this.
In JavaScript it looks like this same thing.
中文字幕
In Python, it looks like this.
So gone are the curly braces.
中文字幕
Added is a colon.
And what you don't see yet is that indentation is going to be important.
中文字幕
So any of you have been a little fast and loose with style 50
and, like we've seen at office hours, all of your code,
中文字幕
however many lines you've written for whatever reason
is all aligned on the left and nothing is actually indented.
中文字幕
Now Python is not going to tolerate that.
Python requires indentation for logic.
中文字幕
And so this is actually a stylistic feature of the language.
It forces you to adopt good visual stylistic habits because the code just
中文字幕
won't run if you haven't indented it properly.
So anything that's going to happen if x is less than y
中文字幕
needs to be indented, say, four spaces underneath that colon.
What else have we seen?
中文字幕
In C or in Scratch we had this block for if's and elses.
In C it looks like this.
中文字幕
In JavaScript it looks like this.
In Python it's going to look like this, albeit with indentation
中文字幕
below each of those colons.
How about this?
中文字幕
When we had three-way a fork in the road-- if else, if else--
in C it looks like this.
中文字幕
JavaScript looked the same.
In Python, looks a little funky.
中文字幕
It's going to look like this--
elif but three colons, this time two.
中文字幕
What else?
We also looked at forever loops in Scratch, in C, and in JavaScript.
中文字幕
You could use exactly the same syntax in Python, almost the same.
Gone are the curly braces, added is the colon.
中文字幕
And the slight subtlety, if you noticed, true and false
are now proper nouns, if you will.
中文字幕
Capital T capital F is necessary to write.
How about a for loop?
中文字幕
So in Scratch, we could very easily say, repeat this 50 times.
C and JavaScript is a little pedantic in that you have
中文字幕
to initialize and increment and check.
Both C and JavaScript take that same approach,
中文字幕
although in JavaScript we of course use let instead of int.
Python is a little more succinct although a little less explicit
中文字幕
step by step.
You just do this.
中文字幕
For i in range of 50 is the way of saying start iterating at 0,
count all the way up to but not including 50,
中文字幕
thereby giving you a range of values.
So this is the one that's perhaps the most weird
中文字幕
thus far, but still a little more succinct to write.
So in C, we had so many data types-- bool, char, double, float, int, long,
中文字幕
string--
the last of which, of course, came from the CS50 library.
中文字幕
And there's others that you can use in C,
as you might recall, from problem set 3, perhaps.
中文字幕
In Python, we're going to shorten this list, at least initially,
to just these data types.
中文字幕
In Python, we're going to have bools for true-false, floats for real numbers,
ints for integers, and then strs for strings.
中文字幕
Just a little more succinct, but it does actually exist. str in Python
is a real thing.
中文字幕
It is not a CS50 addition.
There are other data types that come with Python.
中文字幕
In fact, this is where the language gets powerful.
And those of you who came from a Java background or C++,
中文字幕
the subset of you who have programmed before,
you have more features in Python just like you do in those other languages
中文字幕
that we did not have in C. In Python, you have dictionaries or hash tables.
You have lists, which are arrays, but that can automatically resize.
中文字幕
You don't have to decide in advance how big or small they are.
Range we just saw, it's a range of values, like 50 of them,
中文字幕
set in the mathematical sense.
It's a collection of things that ensures you don't
中文字幕
have duplicates in that collection.
And then tuple is a combination of things kind of like for math
中文字幕
when you have x comma y or latitude comma longitude.
Any time you have pairs or triples or more of things,
中文字幕
those are called tuples.
And those are common in math courses and higher-level CS theory classes,
中文字幕
as well.
But we do give you, at least in this first week
中文字幕
of our look at Python, a few functions from CS50,
among them getFloat, getInt, and getString, which behave exactly
中文字幕
like their C counterparts.
And this is just going to allow us to start
中文字幕
writing code very reminiscent of what we did the last few weeks.
But let's consider what's going to change
中文字幕
as we're about to start writing our own programs.
In C, when you wanted to use the CS50 library, you of course
中文字幕
included its header file.
That syntax is going to change in Python so that for this first week when
中文字幕
you want to use the CS50 library, you're going to instead say
from CS50 import and then a comma separated list of the functions
中文字幕
that you want to import or use in your code.
So it's a little more precise.
中文字幕
This syntax is not saying give me everything.
Give me this, this, and this other thing.
中文字幕
And if you want to use one or more, you can just separate them by commas.
As an aside, especially those of you who have seen Python before,
中文字幕
there's other ways to do this.
There are several approaches.
中文字幕
This is, perhaps, the most comparable for our purposes today.
What else are you're going to have to know?
中文字幕
In C you had to compile your code.
And you did so with clang, like this.
中文字幕
And then you ran your program with dot slash hello.
Or more simply, you did make hello and then
中文字幕
we'd figure out the command for you in the IDE or the sandbox or lab.
In Python, you're going to skip the compilation step.
中文字幕
When you want to run a program in Python,
you're going to do just what I did quickly before.
中文字幕
You're just going to run the command Python and then the name of the file
that you want to run.
中文字幕
And the reason for this is as follows.
In the world of C, recall that we had this sort of pipeline process
中文字幕
where we have our source code as our input.
And then we wanted to get to the point of machine code, the zeros and ones.
中文字幕
And what was standing in between source code and machine code,
just to be clear?
中文字幕
What process?
Yeah, so compiling.
中文字幕
So we had a compiler in the middle whose purpose in life
is by definition to translate one language to another.
中文字幕
It happens to be an English-like language to a computer-like language,
but a compiler is a general term that just converts one thing to another.
中文字幕
And so this pipeline for C looked like this.
And that's why you had to run Clang explicitly, or make.
中文字幕
You had to induce that middle man operation
to convert the language to something the computer understands.
中文字幕
Python and other languages are not typically compiled in the same way.
They're generally said to be interpreted,
中文字幕
whereby you don't compile them into zeros and ones
and then run the program.
中文字幕
You instead run a program that someone else wrote called Python.
And that program is, by definition, an interpreter.
中文字幕
And that interpreter's purpose in life, as the word
implies, is to read your code top to bottom, left to right,
中文字幕
and just do exactly what you tell it to do,
step by step by step, without doing the upfront work of converting things
中文字幕
to zeros and ones.
So in the human world, if I speak English and someone there
中文字幕
speaks Spanish and we don't speak each other's language,
we might put a third human in between us, obviously a human interpreter.
中文字幕
The role is very similar.
The interpreter listens to me and then translates
中文字幕
that to something the computer understands.
But it doesn't get into zeros and ones.
中文字幕
It just goes from one directly to the other.
So the difference here in Python is that you still
中文字幕
are going to write source code, like I quickly did for resize.
And ultimately, we want to actually get it
中文字幕
into a program called an interpreter.
And so the step ideally just looks like this.
中文字幕
But as an aside, Python is a pretty sophisticated language.
And even though we have the pleasure of running it just
中文字幕
with one step instead of these two steps, there actually is, as an aside,
some magic going on underneath the hood.
中文字幕
And for the curious, there actually is, for performance reasons,
a compiler built into Python that actually converts it to something
中文字幕
intermediary called bytecode.
And bytecode is what's actually interpreted.
中文字幕
And so this is why Python, while potentially slower than C
at certain tasks because you're not going to the low level zeros and ones,
中文字幕
can actually be used in business applications and popular websites
and such.
中文字幕
And that didn't really work very well.
And so it can be highly performing, as well.
中文字幕
But more on that in a little bit.
So with that said, if these are the differences not only
中文字幕
syntactically but also mechanically, let's go ahead
and actually write a program.
中文字幕
So let me go ahead and go into the IDE.
Let me close our examples from before.
中文字幕
And let's start more simply because resize was a mouthful all at once.
Let me go ahead and create a file called hello.py.
中文字幕
And instead of writing this program in C,
let me go ahead and just write hello world.
中文字幕
So let's go ahead and do this.
Print hello world.
中文字幕
Done.
That's my first program in Python, and truly my first program in Python,
中文字幕
not sort of coming out swinging with resize.
So what is not present in this file that was in something like hello.c?
中文字幕
There is no main function necessary here.
What else is missing?
中文字幕
Printf.
There is no mention of printf.
中文字幕
It's instead print, which is a little more human friendly.
Libraries.
中文字幕
There is no mention of header files or libraries
at the top of the file.
中文字幕
I just dived right in and got to it.
Yeah?
中文字幕
No semi-colons.
What else?
中文字幕
Yeah?
No backslash n.
中文字幕
I probably-- I haven't run it yet, but I think
I will get that for free this time with Python.
中文字幕
I don't have to be so explicit.
Was there another hand here?
中文字幕
There's no f in printf.
There's no f in printf, yep.
中文字幕
Something else?
There's no indentation.
中文字幕
Though to be fair, there's only one line.
But there's no indentation.
中文字幕
That's fair.
There's no curly braces, as well.
中文字幕
There's no mention of int.
There's no mention of void.
中文字幕
I mean, my God.
Why didn't we just do this last time?
中文字幕
And so this is why languages evolve.
People realized years ago, gee, C is serving us well.
中文字幕
Once I understand pointers and the syntax, OK, I got it.
But my God, it's just so tedious to write even the simplest of programs
中文字幕
because I have to do hash includes, standard io.h, int main void, I mean,
all of this syntactic overhead that's getting in the way of you just
中文字幕
doing the work you care about, which in simplest form
here is just printing hello world.
中文字幕
So Python and a lot of more modern languages-- among them,
Ruby and PHP and others--
中文字幕
just get rid of a lot of that overhead so that you can just get down
to work more quickly right away.
中文字幕
So how do I go ahead and run this?
In C, recall, I would have done dot slash hello.py.
中文字幕
But we just said a moment ago that's not the right approach.
How do I go and run this program?
中文字幕
Yeah, so I run literally a program that is coincidentally called Python itself.
That is the interpreter.
中文字幕
That's the man in the middle between me and my Spanish-speaking friend that
just has to convert hello.py into whatever the computer itself
中文字幕
understands.
And so there, indeed, we have hello world.
中文字幕
And as you notice, there's no backslash n on my code.
But I am moving the cursor to the new line.
中文字幕
So Python just decided, you know what?
It's so damn common to have new lines, let's just add those by default.
中文字幕
You know, the price we're going to pay is it's
a little annoying to get rid of them.
中文字幕
But we'll see that in a little bit, too.
So just a tradeoff.
中文字幕
All right, let's do another one.
That's just a simplest of possible programs.
中文字幕
Let's go ahead and do, say, something a little fancier
that allows us to do something more than that.
中文字幕
So let's go ahead, say, and compare not just
that, but let's actually go get some user input.
中文字幕
So for user input, there's a few ways to do this.
We'll do it the CS50 way initially, but these are training wheels this week
中文字幕
that we'll use for just a week before we take them off,
just bridging us from C to Python.
中文字幕
Let me go ahead and call this string zero.py
because I'm dealing with strings.
中文字幕
And let me go ahead and do s to give me a variable.
Get string.
中文字幕
Let me prompt the human for his or her name like this and then let me go ahead
and say hello.
中文字幕
And so and now I just have to consider how to print out their name.
And in Python, I can actually just do this.
中文字幕
I don't need to do percent s.
I don't need to put a second-- or, I do need to put a second comma here.
中文字幕
But I can just do this, which is a little simpler.
And this is not correct.
中文字幕
I'm not practicing what I preached.
Get rid of the f.
中文字幕
Just print what you want to print, indeed.
So s, notice, is apparently a variable because I'm assigning
中文字幕
it a value from right to left.
But notice that I'm not specifying the type.
中文字幕
So Python does have type. str we said is the string equivalent.
But you don't have to mention it.
中文字幕
Python, like JavaScript, will just figure it out, even without a keyword
like let.
中文字幕
But I do need to add one thing.
What's that?
中文字幕
You need to import the getString?
Yeah, getString is a CS50 thing.
中文字幕
And we're only going to use it for a week, but I do need to import it.
And the syntax with which to do this is to say, from the CS50 library,
中文字幕
import a function called get string.
I don't need to import any more with commas.
中文字幕
That one suffices for this program.
Yeah.
中文字幕
Would you want to--
instead of saying hello your name, would you want to first getName that says
中文字幕
You're not indicating where the error is ..
Sure, let me come back to this in one second.
中文字幕
Let's run this program first to demonstrate that it indeed
does what we saw it do last week.
中文字幕
And let me go ahead here and do this time Python of string 0.
Let me go ahead and it's just waiting for my name.
中文字幕
So I'll type in David.
Hello, David.
中文字幕
But as you propose, what if you wanted to flip this around?
Well, suppose I wanted to say the person's name and then
中文字幕
something like hello because I'm just excited to see them, instead.
Let's see what this does.
中文字幕
Let me go ahead now and run Python of string 0.
Type in my name.
中文字幕
And it's almost what I think you intended.
But there is a bug--
中文字幕
an aesthetic bug, at least.
So it seems with Python's print function you don't need
中文字幕
to use the placeholder like percent s.
But it would seem to presumptuously add a space for you after everything you're
中文字幕
passing in as an input to print itself.
So notice print is taking how many arguments
中文字幕
according to this highlighted portion?
How many arguments might you infer?
中文字幕
S space and then the thing.
Two?
中文字幕
Yeah, so two.
One is s, comma, and then the rest is what's highlighted in green here.
中文字幕
Yes, there's a second comma there, but it's inside of the string.
So just like in C, that's sort of a red herring.
中文字幕
There's only two arguments here.
But it seems that the print function-- and you would know this
中文字幕
by reading that documentation-- if you pass in two or three or more arguments,
it prints all of them.
中文字幕
But separates them with a single space.
So this isn't quite right.
中文字幕
So this is actually a great motivation for cleaning this up.
If I want to actually improve this program and tidy it up a little bit,
中文字幕
let me do that in version one here.
Let me create another file called, say, string1.py.
中文字幕
Let me start where we started a moment ago.
And let me actually use a placeholder akin to C. So if I want to do,
中文字幕
for instance, hello so-and-so, it turns out you can actually say, hey Python,
put a variable called s right here.
中文字幕
However, if I run this as is, there's still going to be a bug.
It's not quite solved yet.
中文字幕
But when I hit Enter now and type in my name--
all right, this is obviously stupid looking.
中文字幕
So it seems that I need to tell Python that this string that I'm passing in,
hello comma so and so, is a formatted string.
中文字幕
It's a placeholder string that it should make some changes to.
And this is a little weird, cryptic syntactically in Python.
中文字幕
But the way you do this in Python is you put an f before the string itself.
So I'm sorry, we got rid of the f a moment ago.
中文字幕
So we just called it print.
Now we're reusing a different f here.
中文字幕
And it's stupid-looking syntax, admittedly.
But this just means hey, Python, the following double quotes
中文字幕
or single quotes that you're about to see should
be formatted by you in a special way.
中文字幕
And it literally goes at the beginning of the string
even though that does admittedly look weird.
中文字幕
But if I now rerun this Python string one and type in my name now,
now it does the substitution.
中文字幕
So I can flip it around logically much more flexibly now
and do something like hello because now I'm passing in one argument
中文字幕
that print will format for me.
So when I type in my name now, I'm not going to get that superfluous space.
中文字幕
And now I have complete control over the formatting of the string.
So you know, sort of two steps forward, one step back, perhaps, syntactically.
中文字幕
But it does allow us to do what we want this to do.
We could write the same program using ints
中文字幕
and floats using getInt and getFloat.
Would look exactly the same.
中文字幕
You don't need to worry about percent s versus percent i versus percent f.
You just type in the variable name inside of those curly braces.
中文字幕
All right, let me go ahead and do some quick math.
Let me go ahead and do this.
中文字幕
Let me go ahead and create a new file.
We'll call this ints.py for integers.
中文字幕
And let me go ahead and get this access to--
how about the CS50 library's get int method or function which exists.
中文字幕
Then let me go ahead and declare a variable
called x and get an int from the user and just prompt him or her for x.
中文字幕
Then let me go ahead and do the same thing
and just get y from them, as well.
中文字幕
And then down here, let me just do some simple math.
And we did this way back in week one by printing as follows.
中文字幕
Let me go ahead and just print out x plus y equals--
and this is what's cool now about this curly brace feature.
中文字幕
You can actually do not just variable's names,
but you can do simple operations in there, too.
中文字幕
I can literally do math inside of those curly braces and print out that value.
But of course, this alone is just going to literally print the curly braces.
中文字幕
What do I have to add?
Yeah, so it looks a little weird.
中文字幕
But this now will solve that problem.
It will print literally x plus y equals whatever the actual sum is.
中文字幕
Just following up, what does f mean?
Format.
中文字幕
Format the following string for me.
Good question.
中文字幕
Let's do just a few copy/paste but change the operator here.
So x minus y, I want to see what this looks like.
中文字幕
X, say-- what did we do last time?
Multiplying by y.
中文字幕
I want to do that math, too.
I can divide as well.
中文字幕
And then we had one more, which was modulo,
or modular arithmetic, which, recall, was the percent sign.
中文字幕
So syntactically, it's identical to see.
We're just adding this curly brace notation just for the print function
中文字幕
right now.
Let me go ahead and run this.
中文字幕
Python of ints.py.
And let me go ahead and do one and say two.
中文字幕
So 1 plus 2 is 3.
1 minus 2 is negative 1.
中文字幕
1 times 2 is 2.
1 divided by 2 is 0.5.
中文字幕
And 1 then divide by 2 and take the remainder is 1.
So I think this checks out mathematically.
中文字幕
But you should be a little surprised by one of these outcomes.
Say again?
中文字幕
You're getting a float.
Yeah, I'm getting a float.
中文字幕
Like, Python itself seems to have fixed a bug in C itself.
What happened in C when you divided 1, an integer, by 2, an integer, in C?
中文字幕
You would get another integer.
And what's the closest integer you can represent
中文字幕
that doesn't have a decimal point?
0, because the C would truncate everything after the decimal point.
中文字幕
And yet, Python seems to have fixed this problem.
And this is actually a somewhat recent phenomenon.
中文字幕
And this a huge religious debate as to whether or not
you should just keep the historical definition of division, which
中文字幕
is floor division, so to speak, or we should make it truly division,
like we all grew up learning in school.
中文字幕
Python took the latter approach and made division mean division, true division,
where if you divide two ints you get back a float.
中文字幕
Of course, this is a problem if people want
to write code that assumes that it's going to be truncated.
中文字幕
That can actually be a powerful feature.
So it turns out, and you won't have terribly many occasions to use this,
中文字幕
but the compromise in the world was, all right, if you really
want the old behavior of the division in Python, we will give it back to you.
中文字幕
You have to use two slashes.
So again, another one of these two steps forward, one step back.
中文字幕
But it's there, so problems can still be solved in the same way.
And this, if I save it and rerun that same code, 1 and 2,
中文字幕
now I get back 0, just as I would in C, which does have some applicability.
Let's do one other example now involving some numbers.
中文字幕
And let me go ahead and call this floats.py.
And let me do the same thing, from CS50 import getFloat this time.
中文字幕
So I can deal with floating point values.
Let me declare a variable x and get a float
中文字幕
and we'll ask the user for a variable x.
Then let's go ahead and get another float, and just as before, call it y.
中文字幕
But this time both of them are, indeed, floats.
Then let me go ahead and do some math, x plus y equals z.
中文字幕
Let's give myself a third variable.
And then let me just go ahead and print out a similar message--
中文字幕
x divided by y equals z.
All right, and let me go ahead and save this, clear my terminal,
中文字幕
and do Python of floats.py.
1 divided by 10 this time.
中文字幕
And I get-- dammit, bug.
How do I fix this?
中文字幕
All right, so just a simple f.
Make it a format string.
中文字幕
No big deal.
So let's rerun this, 1, 10.
中文字幕
OK, hoo, hoo.
That's a new one.
中文字幕
What is going on there?
I did define z in the line above it, and what was your comment?
中文字幕
You used x plus y.
I did use x plus y, but I think I--
中文字幕
oh, wait, OK.
I'm sorry.
中文字幕
Let's-- OK, so we can fix that.
Let's-- sorry.
中文字幕
There.
OK, so 110.
中文字幕
Hmm, still wrong.
Good catch, thank you, though.
中文字幕
Why is 1 plus 2 11--
or 1 plus 10, 11?
中文字幕
Yeah?
.
中文字幕
Wait, wait, wait.
Sorry.
中文字幕
This brings me back to my earlier point as to how tired I am.
So this is correct.
中文字幕
So Python does math correctly.
But-- OK, horrifying.
中文字幕
All right, so now let's do division and try
to make the point I think I meant to make late last night where I if I do 1
中文字幕
divided by 10, OK, 1 divided by 10, as expected, does actually work here.
So 0.1, that's correct.
中文字幕
But remember in C-- let me dig myself out of this hole--
remember in C what happened if we dug a little deeper
中文字幕
and we looked a little past the first decimal point.
So how do I do this in Python?
中文字幕
It's actually pretty similar.
Let me go ahead and not just show myself z but go ahead
中文字幕
and print out to, let's say, two decimal places that same value.
The syntax here is weird.
中文字幕
It's different from C. But you literally take the variable that you want
to format, you put a colon and then a dot--
中文字幕
because you want to adjust the dot--
and then you want to say something like 2f.
中文字幕
So this is saying, hey, Python, format the variable
that's to the left of the colon using two decimal points.
中文字幕
And by the way, it's a floating point value.
So this f has a different meaning.
中文字幕
This is f as in float.
The f to the left is in format.
中文字幕
So let me go ahead and run this.
1 divided by 10.
中文字幕
And OK, still looking pretty good.
Let's do maybe three decimal places, save that, rerun it.
中文字幕
1 divided by 10.
Still pretty good.
中文字幕
Let's get a little ambitious.
Let's do it 50 decimal places out, 1 divided by 10, and damn it.
中文字幕
Python has not fixed this fundamental problem.
So we describe this problem as what?
中文字幕
What's the sort of buzzword here to sort of explain or forgive this issue?
This is an integer overflow, related in spirit.
中文字幕
Integer overflow literally happens when you're
doing lots of addition and something's rolling over from a big value
中文字幕
to a small or even a negative.
Similar in spirit.
中文字幕
Yeah?
Yeah.
中文字幕
If you want to have an infinite amount of precision all the way out,
you need an infinite amount of memory.
中文字幕
And no Mac or PC or phone has an infinite amount of memory.
At some point, a line is drawn in the sand and you can only be so precise.
中文字幕
And so imprecision was the analog in the floating point world
to overflow, recall, where if you only have a finite number of bits
中文字幕
you can do really well up to a point.
But eventually, the computer's got to estimate that value for you
中文字幕
because you can't represent an infinite number of values.
So this is to say Python is just as limited, fundamentally,
中文字幕
as some other languages like C. So we've not
gotten rid of all of those problems.
中文字幕
But frankly, in the world of data science and analytics,
it's certainly important precise mathematics.
中文字幕
So there are solutions to this problem.
But it requires special libraries, typically,
中文字幕
importing something that allows you to use as much memory
as you want more than just the default amount of memory.
中文字幕
So that problem there still exists.
Let me go ahead and open up one other example here.
中文字幕
And in fact, in C, you'll recall that we had this example here.
In C we had a program called overflow.c.
中文字幕
And notice that this code in C from a few weeks
back just multiplied i by 2, by 2, by 2.
中文字幕
So it was doing exponentiation, so to speak--
1 to 2 to 4 to 8, 16, 32, 64, and so forth.
中文字幕
What happened if we waited long enough and watched
this program a few weeks back?
中文字幕
You go to 5 billion instead of--
Yeah, we hit roughly 5 billion or 4 billion--
中文字幕
or rather, we technically hit, I think, 2 billion, and then it rolled over.
And it actually created a problem.
中文字幕
So let me actually do this.
Let me go ahead and make overflow so we can demonstrate
中文字幕
the points that you made earlier about integer overflow, which is, indeed,
this one.
中文字幕
Let me go ahead now and run overflow.
I'll expand my window just so we can fit a little more in the screen.
中文字幕
And as this runs--
whoops, let me fix this.
中文字幕
Here we go.
Let me go ahead and make overflow.
中文字幕
And now 1, 2, 4, 8, 16, 32, and so forth.
It's a little slow to start, but doubling and doubling
中文字幕
is going to get us up to a big value pretty quickly.
This is indeed going to overflow once we hit roughly 2 billion.
中文字幕
Why?
Why two billion, give or take?
中文字幕
Why that value in C?
Yeah?
中文字幕
Yeah, that's how much an integer
can store because we're calling C. An int is typically 32 bits or 4 bytes.
中文字幕
And with 32 bits, you can represent four billion possible values.
And if half of those values are positive and half of them are negative,
中文字幕
it stands to reason that the highest you can count is roughly 2 billion.
And indeed, once we try to count up just doubling one billion, we overflow.
中文字幕
So to your point earlier, overflow is still an issue,
but in the context of integers.
中文字幕
But now let's try a Python version of this.
Let me go ahead now and open up overflow.py,
中文字幕
which is a program I wrote in advance.
It's on the course's website, as always, if you
中文字幕
want to take a look more closely.
And if I go into this file in weeks one, overflow.py, we see this code.
中文字幕
So it's almost the same.
But notice I'm using another library that we've not
中文字幕
seen before, from time import sleep.
It's kind of cute.
中文字幕
So this allows me to sleep for a second.
That's going to get tedious quickly, but that's OK.
中文字幕
Let's do this real fast.
If I go into the source six directory, weeks one,
中文字幕
and run Python of overflow.py, it's the same function-- or same program,
functionally.
中文字幕
But honestly, this is getting a little tedious.
Let's go ahead and not sleep for a second every time, save and reload.
中文字幕
Let's just run the thing.
Whew, look at it go.
中文字幕
Only up there.
Look up there.
中文字幕
What's it doing differently?
It's counting a lot higher than 2 billion.
中文字幕
So what might you infer about integers in Python?
Say again?
中文字幕
An integer is defined to be quite a number of bits.
OK, an integer is defined to be quite a number of bits.
中文字幕
And indeed, that's the case.
Python is not actually this slow.
中文字幕
It's because we're running a web based IDE and the internet itself
is a little slow.
中文字幕
And so what's happening here is just the internet is getting in the way.
But suffice it to say that Python is counting up way, way higher than C was.
中文字幕
And that's the power you get by just using larger data types.
We could have done this in C. We could have used longs, for instance.
中文字幕
But notice that with Python you just get more by default out of the box.
Let's go ahead and take a five minute break here.
中文字幕
And when we resume, we'll introduce some more syntax
and solve some more problems.
中文字幕
All right, so let's take a look at a few other examples
that are comparable to what we did back in week one and look at a few
中文字幕
from week two and three and really take a look
not just at the syntax, ultimately, but some of the features of Python.
中文字幕
And of course, we need the ability to express ourselves conditionally
or logically with control flow.
中文字幕
And so let me propose a quick program here
that we'll just call conditions.py, reminiscent of conditions.c
中文字幕
some time ago.
Let me go ahead and import from CS50 getInt this time
中文字幕
and get myself another x with getInt x from the user.
Then let me go ahead and ask them for getInt y from the user.
中文字幕
And then let me go ahead and just compare them.
And so per our comparison with Scratch a bit ago,
中文字幕
I can simply say if x is less than y, then go ahead
and print out, for instance, print x is less than y, just as we did weeks ago.
中文字幕
Elif if x is greater than y, we can go ahead
and print out x is greater than y.
中文字幕
And then we can still have a third condition, else, just
like in C, where we print out, for instance, the logical conclusion.
中文字幕
x is equal to y.
So just to point out some of the differences,
中文字幕
indentation is ever so important now.
And it's got to be consistent.
中文字幕
You can't have four spaces and three.
You've got to have, for instance, four all the way.
中文字幕
Notice that I've got the colons consistently there.
But notice that I don't need the parentheses, either, anymore.
中文字幕
And with Python, there's sort of a buzzword, Pythonic.
There is a Pythonic way of doing things.
中文字幕
You can have parentheses around x, less than y, or x greater than y,
just like in C. But it doesn't add anything logically, arguably.
中文字幕
And if it doesn't make your code more readable,
don't clutter your code with additional characters.
中文字幕
And so that's a general rule of thumb now.
Python is much more trim when it comes to syntax, only
中文字幕
introducing it when it really solves a problem, which in this case,
it doesn't really.
中文字幕
Yeah?
Quick question, the lines ,,
中文字幕
those are grouped right together, one to the next, one to the next,
and one to the next.
中文字幕
If you were to put an additional line between them,
would that break the code?
中文字幕
No, not at all.
I can have as much whitespace vertically as I want if.
中文字幕
I want to add some comments, indeed, I can do that.
And why don't we do that, in fact, because the commenting syntax
中文字幕
for Python is a little different.
In C, we were in the habit of doing slash slash.
中文字幕
Python, it's actually a little more succinct.
You can just use a single hash.
中文字幕
And you can say gets x from user here.
I can say get y from user here.
中文字幕
And then I can say something like compare x and y.
And if I really wanted to, I could put comments in here.
中文字幕
That is perfectly fine.
But I'll just keep it more compact with this particular example.
中文字幕
So any questions on the conditional syntax or what we've just done here?
All right, let Me whip up another example,
中文字幕
this time doing some comparisons.
This time, let me create a file called answer.py,
中文字幕
which is reminiscent of a quick example we did weeks ago called answer.c.
Let me go ahead and from CS50 import getString.
中文字幕
And this time, let me go ahead and declare
a variable, C. And let me go ahead and get a string from the user--
中文字幕
whoops-- get a string from the user for their answer
to whatever question it is we care about.
中文字幕
And then if it's meant to be a yes/no answer, let's check for that.
If c equals equals y or c equals equals little y,
中文字幕
then go ahead and say, just for the sake of demonstration,
yes, because the human presumably meant that.
中文字幕
Elif c equals equals capital n or c equals equals little n,
then go ahead and print out, for instance, no.
中文字幕
So a short program, but what are some of the takeaways?
Well, what's different clearly among these lines, 5 through 8, versus C,
中文字幕
weeks ago?
Yeah.
中文字幕
For or you have to do--
Yeah, none of those stupid vertical bars or the ampersand
中文字幕
ampersand.
If you want to do something or or and it together, just say and and
中文字幕
or, much like Scratch, actually, some weeks ago.
Notice, too-- how are we comparing strings?
中文字幕
Turns out Python does not have chars, per se.
C did have chars, single characters.
中文字幕
Python only has strings.
It has strings, ints, floats, and then some fancier things,
中文字幕
but it doesn't have chars.
So that's why I am deliberately using string.
中文字幕
But when we use strings in C, how did we compare two strings?
Str comp, right, because of the whole annoying pointer comparison thing.
中文字幕
Well, it turns out now in Python if you want
to compare two strings character by character by character,
中文字幕
equal equals is back.
And it does exactly what you expect it to do, even if it's a full word.
中文字幕
So if you're actually checking for, for instance, yes or yes from the human,
you can still use equal equals, as well, even though it's
中文字幕
more than now one character.
So that's a wonderful feature, too.
中文字幕
And it just makes the code more readable and a lot easier
to write right out of the gate.
中文字幕
All right, so now recall that in C we spent a little while,
as well as in Scratch, taking a look at a few examples about coughing,
中文字幕
of all things.
And in fact, in Python and C--
中文字幕
rather, in Scratch and in C--
we did a zero example that looked a little like this.
中文字幕
If you want to simulate the notion of Scratch the cat coughing,
you might, of course, do this.
中文字幕
And then if he's going to cough three times, you might do this.
And we ran this and it just did cough, cough, cough on the screen.
中文字幕
I won't bother running it because it will just do that.
But this was bad design we claimed weeks ago.
中文字幕
What was the gist of why this is bad design?
I mean, I literally copied and pasted.
中文字幕
And the odds are if you're ever doing that in CS50 or in programming
more generally, you're probably being a little lazy
中文字幕
and there's a better way to do it.
And it's a more maintainable way to do it.
中文字幕
So of course, we introduced weeks ago, both in Scratch and in C,
the ability to in cough one, this time, do a loop.
中文字幕
And I can do a loop slightly differently in Python and in C. But for i
in the range of 3, go ahead and print out cough.
中文字幕
So the syntax for the for loop is a little different.
But it's pretty straightforward, nonetheless,
中文字幕
once you remember that you use for, variable name, then
the preposition in, and then the word range with a parenthesis and its--
中文字幕
parentheses and the value you want to care about.
But then we saw an opportunity, recall, to actually abstract coughing away.
中文字幕
Coughing, at least in our textual form, is just the act of printing something.
So we introduced in version two some time ago,
中文字幕
the following approach in cough two.
I instead defined a function called cough that did the coughing for me.
中文字幕
And we've not seen this yet in Python.
So how do you define a function in Python called cough?
中文字幕
Put another way, how do you make your own custom puzzle piece,
just as we did in Scratch?
中文字幕
Well, you define it with def.
And then you have it do exactly what you want
中文字幕
it to do by just indenting the lines of code that belong to that function.
So there's no return value.
中文字幕
There's no need for an input at the moment.
But we do have the colon.
中文字幕
And we have the indentation.
No curly braces, nothing else.
中文字幕
How do I now use this function?
Well, here's where we have a few options stylistically in the program.
中文字幕
The simplest way to call this function would be quite simply like this.
Go ahead and for i in range 3, go ahead now and cough.
中文字幕
And this should look a little weird.
It looks, indeed, a little sloppy.
中文字幕
But let's see if it works.
So if I go ahead and run Python of coughtwo.py,
中文字幕
it seems to cough, cough, cough.
But I say this is a little weird because what am I
中文字幕
doing that's very different now from C?
There's no what?
中文字幕
There's no main function.
I just have some code right here on the left of the screen.
中文字幕
And yet, I do have a function here.
And in Python, this is OK.
中文字幕
Because you're using an interpreter and reading the file
top to bottom, left to right, you don't strictly need a function called main.
中文字幕
It's just going to interpret all of your code.
And when it's seen the definition of a function, OK.
中文字幕
It's going to say, OK, got it.
I now know what the verb cough means.
中文字幕
I will do this anytime I see it down here.
But we're going to run into a problem.
中文字幕
And if, indeed, I did what my first instinct was,
which was to put the logic, the main part of my program at the top
中文字幕
and to define cough down here, let's see what happens.
Let me zoom out.
中文字幕
Let me go ahead and rerun coughtwo.py.
And now we start to see the first of our error messages.
中文字幕
And they're going to look just as cryptic at first glance as is clang
and make were.
中文字幕
Arrested assured that help 50 can help with Python error messages, as well.
But let's just try to parse what I do understand. cough2.py, line two
中文字幕
in module whatever that is, name error.
Name cough is not defined.
中文字幕
So what's your gut here?
What is that really--
中文字幕
what's the explanation for that error?
Because cough is clearly defined--
中文字幕
literally with the define def verb--
right there on line four now.
中文字幕
What--
You're calling cough before it's defined.
中文字幕
Yeah, I'm trying to call it before it's defined.
Python is trying to take me very literally.
中文字幕
And it's going to do top to bottom, left to right.
And if it doesn't see until the bottom something
中文字幕
it's supposed to be doing at the top, it's just not going to work.
So there is a solution to this and it starts to get a little ugly.
中文字幕
But it's a more generalized solution.
It turns out that even though main is not required in a Python program,
中文字幕
many programmers just create one nonetheless
to address this particular problem.
中文字幕
And they specifically do something like this--
def main-- and then below it they indent everything there.
中文字幕
And then you need one specific feature to solve this problem now.
I've now defined main and I've defined cough, which theoretically
中文字幕
solves this problem just as it did in C. There
is no notion of a prototype in Python.
中文字幕
That is not the solution to copy paste the name of the function up above.
But when I do this now, literally nothing happens.
中文字幕
But I did get rid of the error.
So just reason through this, perhaps.
中文字幕
Especially if you've never programmed Python before,
why might nothing now be happening?
中文字幕
Not calling main?
I'm not calling main, yeah.
中文字幕
So whereas in C--
and frankly, in Java, C++, and a few other languages-- main is special.
中文字幕
It just gets called by default. In Python, main is not special.
I've chosen this name main just because so many other languages use it,
中文字幕
but it has no special significance.
If you want to call main, you have to do it yourself.
中文字幕
And so this is a little weird, admittedly.
But you can literally do this down here because your code will be executed top
中文字幕
to bottom, left to right.
By the time line 10 is reached, both main has been defined
中文字幕
and cough has been defined, which means you're good to go.
So if I now go down here and run Python of cough2, now it actually works.
中文字幕
Now, as an aside, this is not Pythonic, if you will.
Most people would actually do this if the name equals equals main,
中文字幕
then do this.
This is for lower level reasons that let me wave my hand out for today.
中文字幕
But long story short, the addition of this cryptic-looking line
solves other problems that we're just not going
中文字幕
to trip over this week and probably next.
So this is the common way to do it.
中文字幕
But if you just ignore that, the effect of this cryptic-looking code
is just to call main yourself at the very bottom of your file.
中文字幕
So when we start writing more interesting programs,
this is just going to become conventional.
中文字幕
If you want to start writing functions and so forth,
odds are you'll benefit by writing a main function
中文字幕
and putting more code in there.
So let's do one final example with cough that actually now parameterizes
中文字幕
the code, just as we did weeks ago in Scratch and C. This will be cough3.py.
Let me start as I did just a little bit ago.
中文字幕
But suppose I want to achieve this effect.
I want the computer to cough three times by passing in an input.
中文字幕
I now do need to modify cough to take an input.
And in C, I would have said something like int n.
中文字幕
But you don't have to specify data types in Python,
you just have to specify the parameter name or the argument name.
中文字幕
So that's nice and simple.
And now down in here, in cough is where I should probably
中文字幕
say for i in the range of 3, do this.
But this isn't quite right.
中文字幕
What fix do I want to make here?
Yeah.
中文字幕
Now I can just pass in n.
So range is just a function that takes an argument that I've
中文字幕
been hard coding as three just because.
But you can generalize it with n, as well.
中文字幕
So now again, per our discussion of abstraction weeks and weeks
ago, do we have a sort of beautiful version of coughing,
中文字幕
even though it's looking way more cryptic.
But by step by step by step did we get to the point
中文字幕
of having a main function that takes an abstraction, cough.
Do it this many times.
中文字幕
Now the implementation details are hidden in this custom puzzle piece,
if you will.
中文字幕
And the two lines at the bottom just kick off
the whole execution of the program.
中文字幕
But that's the only stuff that's really Python-specific now.
Yeah?
中文字幕
Can we use the cough function on line 11 ??
Could use the cough function on line 11?
中文字幕
Yes.
You could absolutely just do this, for instance, and get rid of main again.
中文字幕
It's just a convention.
Once you start writing more sophisticated programs with functions,
中文字幕
you should probably introduce main just to keep it tidy.
With the .
中文字幕
You could do that.
Then you're starting to be non-Pythonic.
中文字幕
Like, yes, you could do cough3 but people would look askew at you
because it's just not done that way.
中文字幕
That's what Pythonic means.
Yeah, other questions?
中文字幕
You need to have the  come after the for i
in range n so that it knows what the cough is?
中文字幕
Not in this case.
So the order now is OK because first Python is seeing here's
中文字幕
the definition of main.
OK, I got it.
中文字幕
And then it's saying, here is the definition of cough, OK, I got it.
But it's not actually calling those functions yet.
中文字幕
The Python errors are thrown only at what's called runtime,
the running of the program's time, which means only when main is called
中文字幕
does Python actually execute line 4 and then see,
ooh, I need to call a function called cough.
中文字幕
But that's OK because it saw it earlier when it first
read the file top to bottom.
中文字幕
So it matters when the functions are called,
not where they appear, per se, in the file, the order in which they're
中文字幕
called.
Other questions?
中文字幕
All right, yes?
I don't know where you  from.
中文字幕
How do you define n as an integer?
How did I define n as an integer?
中文字幕
This is what's nice about Python.
If you want a variable or a parameter, just
中文字幕
start using it without mentioning its data type.
So the fact that I put n in parentheses in this function
中文字幕
means, hey, Python, let this function take an input called n.
And it can actually be any data type-- int, float, string,
中文字幕
or even something else.
It's up to me to use it responsibly as a number
中文字幕
and to call it responsibly with a number.
Good question.
中文字幕
Yeah?
So it's possible for a variable to change type?
中文字幕
It is, indeed, possible for a variable
to change type, a good observation.
中文字幕
So yes, Python is not as strongly-typed language, so to speak.
C is strongly-typed in that if you make something an int,
中文字幕
it is staying an int forever.
Python is loosely typed, whereby x can be an int initially.
中文字幕
But if you really want to turn it into a string, you can.
But the convention there would be, yes, you can do that, but don't do that.
中文字幕
So Python has the, frankly, the sort of arrogance
of being sort of an adult language.
中文字幕
Yes, you could do that, but just don't.
Why do we have to protect you from yourselves?
中文字幕
And so in that sense, you need to be a little more responsible about it.
But again, there are arguments both ways.
中文字幕
That induces potential bugs that C would catch for you.
And this is where humans start to disagree about the upsides
中文字幕
and downsides of languages, whether a language should be strongly or loosely
or not even typed at all.
中文字幕
A good observation.
So let's look at a paradigm that was super common in C
中文字幕
when we wanted to do something again and again
to see how it actually is a little differently done in Python now.
中文字幕
Let me go ahead and create a file called positive.py
and go ahead and write a program a little quickly here.
中文字幕
So from CS50, let me go ahead and import getInt,
so we can get integers from the user.
中文字幕
Let me go ahead and define a main function
that simply does i, which will be my variable, gets a positive int,
中文字幕
and asks the user, just as we did weeks ago,
if you'll recall, for a positive integer.
中文字幕
And then just goes ahead and very boringly prints it out.
So that's all this program does.
中文字幕
And let me go ahead and just from recollection--
though it's totally fine to copy/paste this cryptic-looking string,
中文字幕
we would just be remiss in not showing you how most people do this.
So if I do this, this is a complete program,
中文字幕
except for the fact that what does not exist yet?
Get positive int probably does not exist, just as it didn't in week one,
中文字幕
because we have to invent it ourselves.
Get int exists, but get positive int does not.
中文字幕
And just for demonstration's sake, let's try this.
Python of positive.py, notice we have name error get
中文字幕
positive int not defined.
OK, so we can fix that.
中文字幕
We can literally define, or def, it.
So get positive int.
中文字幕
It's going to take a prompt from the user,
just as it did weeks ago, the string that you want to show to him or her.
中文字幕
And now let me go ahead and get a positive integer.
What type of programming construct did we
中文字幕
use in C to do something again and again and again?
Loop.
中文字幕
A loop, for sure, but more specifically,
to do something at least once and then maybe again
中文字幕
and again and again if they don't cooperate?
While.
中文字幕
Do while.
No do while in Python.
中文字幕
So that handy feature for user input does not exist.
So that's fine.
中文字幕
We need to solve this just differently.
And honestly, in C, you could have solved that problem differently.
中文字幕
You don't need do while.
We could have taken it away from you.
中文字幕
C could take it away.
You could still solve every problem that we have in the past weeks
中文字幕
using a for loop or a while loop.
Do while just is a nice handy feature.
中文字幕
But we can simulate it.
And the Pythonic way of doing this is as follows.
中文字幕
Deliberately induce an infinite loop, because you
do want to loop potentially.
中文字幕
But the logic is going to be, give me an infinite loop
and I will break out of it when I'm ready to break out of it.
中文字幕
This would be the convention.
So while the following is true do this.
中文字幕
Go ahead and declare a variable called n.
Get an int from the user and pass in that same prompt.
中文字幕
So get int, we wrote-- the staff--
prompt is whatever I typed in up here.
中文字幕
So just copy/paste from the C version.
And then under what circumstances do I want to break out of this infinite loop
中文字幕
if the function is to be called to get positive int?
Yeah, so if n is greater than 0,
中文字幕
then I do have the keyword break still, just as I did in C.
I can break out of this loop.
中文字幕
And then once I do that, I can go ahead and just return n.
Or for that matter, I could condense this a little bit.
中文字幕
I could just return n immediately and tighten it just a little bit.
So multiple ways to do this.
中文字幕
Otherwise it's just going to loop and loop forever.
So let me go ahead now and run positive.py
中文字幕
through Python, positive integer like negative 1, maybe negative 2, 0, OK, 1.
And now it, indeed, co-operates.
中文字幕
So this is just a common paradigm.
This is the kind of thing when learning a new language that honestly
中文字幕
tends to hang people up initially.
You need to learn the JavaScript way of doing things.
中文字幕
You need to learn the Python way of doing things.
But then you start to notice these so-called design patterns.
中文字幕
Anytime in Python you want to do something again and again,
yes, you want to loop.
中文字幕
But if you want to do something definitely once and maybe again?
You still just use a loop, but you deliberately
中文字幕
induce, typically, an infinite loop, and just break out of it when you're ready.
So a very common approach.
中文字幕
So not everything translates literally from C back and forth.
Any questions then on that?
中文字幕
Yeah, in the back?
Is that something you just did with the while for loop,
中文字幕
is that  initializing a variable called
to a negative number and then do while n is less than 0--
中文字幕
Really good question.
Is this approach preferable to instead declaring, maybe
中文字幕
in here, a variable that is equal to some known value, like zero or whatnot,
and then updating it?
中文字幕
Short answer, yes, because your approach, while correct,
is not as well-designed, arguably because it's just not necessary.
中文字幕
And the Pythonic way, and really the well-designed way
to do most things would be use as few lines
中文字幕
as you can so long as it's still readable and understandable,
which I would argue this is once you're comfortable with the syntax.
中文字幕
But this does bring up an interesting point about one other topic in C. Scope
has now gone out the window, at least as we previously saw it.
中文字幕
Scope referred to where a variable lives.
And we defined it essentially casually between two curly braces,
中文字幕
the most recently opened curly braces.
Well, no curly braces anymore so it turns out that variables by default
中文字幕
have function scope here.
So when you declare n on line 9, you can use it in Python on line 10.
中文字幕
And you know what?
You can even use it on line 12, even though it was declared inside
中文字幕
of this loop higher up.
So once you declare a variable on this line,
中文字幕
you can use it anywhere on a subsequent line within that same function.
So in some sense, it's a little sloppy that you're allowed to do this.
中文字幕
But on the other hand, it's very convenient
because you don't have to deal with those things
中文字幕
like declaring the variable up here just to use it down here.
So it's one less thing to think about.
中文字幕
All right, let's take a look just a few examples from week two
wherein we introduced arrays and strings more generally
中文字幕
to see what has changed now, as well.
You'll recall that in week two, perhaps, we had an example about capitalization.
中文字幕
And let me go ahead and look at the third version of that,
capitalize too, but convert it to Python.
中文字幕
The purpose in life was to take input from the user
and just capitalize every character therein.
中文字幕
So if I type in my name in all lowercase,
it should come back as all uppercase.
中文字幕
So from the CS50 library, let me go ahead
and import getString so that I have some input from the user.
中文字幕
Then let me go ahead and just get a string from the user, like their name.
And then I want to go ahead and capitalize everything.
中文字幕
So let me go ahead and do this.
And this is a fancy feature.
中文字幕
In C I would have done a for int i is zero i less than strlen.
I mean, you perhaps remember the paradigm for iterating over a string.
中文字幕
Python is just so much more pleasant.
For c in s--
中文字幕
that will induce a loop over the string s, giving you access to every character
at a time, calling that variable c.
中文字幕
And so what is it I want to do, just as a preliminary step,
a baby step, if you will, let's just print out c, just to see what happens.
中文字幕
Let me go ahead down here and do Python of capitalize two.
Let me go ahead and type in my name, all lowercase.
中文字幕
All right, and why is it showing up vertically
like that, one character per line?
中文字幕
Yeah, you get the free line--
free new line this time.
中文字幕
So let's see how you can disable that.
It's stupid looking, honestly.
中文字幕
But you say end equals quote unquote, thereby revealing a new feature
of Python that C does not have.
中文字幕
It turns out that Python has not only positional arguments, as it's called,
whereby you just pass in arguments between commas.
中文字幕
That's what we've been doing in C.
But Python also has named arguments, whereby
中文字幕
you can specify the name of the argument,
then an equals sign, then the value.
中文字幕
And the power of named arguments, even though this is a tiny example,
means that you can sometimes pass in your arguments in any order.
中文字幕
You don't have to remember.
You don't have to pull up CS50 manual or the man pages
中文字幕
to remember what is the order of all these darn arguments.
You can pass them in in any order, but by specifying
中文字幕
the name of the argument, an equals sign, and its value.
And in Python 2, you can have optional arguments.
中文字幕
Obviously, in all of the examples thus far,
I have never typed the word end and an equals sign yet.
中文字幕
But what Python does support is default values for arguments.
And so if you look in the documentation for Python, this is equivalent--
中文字幕
this cryptic looking sequence-- this is equivalent to the default behavior,
which is to type none of that at all.
中文字幕
End implies, for the print function, that you should end every line
with that default character.
中文字幕
Therefore, if you want to override it, you
can just change it to the empty string, quote unquote.
中文字幕
So if I now run this again and run it through with my name,
now I get it like that, one character at a time.
中文字幕
But you can do weird things, like ha ha ha ha ha--
not that you would.
中文字幕
I don't know why I went with that.
But I mean, that does the exact same thing
中文字幕
because you're just changing the line ending.
So don't do that, but do something else like this with it, instead.
中文字幕
So suppose I want to now capitalize the first character.
It turns out that strings in Python are more powerful than strings
中文字幕
in C. In C, there is no string.
That was a lie.
中文字幕
It's just a sequence of characters as referenced by an address in memory.
In Python, a string is an actual object.
中文字幕
It's a data structure.
And if you think about C, we had structs toward the very end of our look
中文字幕
at C, nodes and structs and student structures and the like.
A string in Python is like this container inside of which
中文字幕
somewhere are all of those characters.
But in that container or structure is also built-in functions,
中文字幕
features of a string that you can just call.
So in C, we would have said something like toUpper
中文字幕
and then passed as input to a function called toUpper
the character that we care about.
中文字幕
Python kind of flips the logic around.
Strings come with built-in functionality that
中文字幕
allow you to operate on the given character automatically.
So in Python, the syntax is actually the character itself.
中文字幕
Use the dot notation because it's a structure.
And then you can literally do--
中文字幕
oops.
You can literally do upper.
中文字幕
So this is to say, built into the string type in Python
is a bunch of features, one of which is a function called upper.
中文字幕
And the syntax with which you call it is the name of the variable
or the name of the string dot name of the function open paren, close paren.
中文字幕
And that's just now the paradigm.
There's no C type library.
中文字幕
There's no to upper or to lower.
Those features now built into the strings themselves.
中文字幕
And this is an example of encapsulation, or more
generally, object oriented programming, something
中文字幕
you'll explore if you take a class like CS51 that
bakes into the data types itself all of the relevant functionality.
中文字幕
It does not relegate them to another library.
So if I clean this up by just moving the cursor to the next line,
中文字幕
now hopefully you'll indeed see David typed out in all caps, the same idea
as before.
中文字幕
What about this length of a string?
This one is pretty trivial, but if I go in here,
中文字幕
let me go ahead and create a file called str len of .py.
If I want to see the length of a string, from CS50 import getString,
中文字幕
just as we did before.
Let me go ahead and get a string for myself, like my name again.
中文字幕
And then here, if I want to print the length of the string, in Python--
in C, you would say strlen.
中文字幕
In Python, it's a little different.
You actually just say len for length.
中文字幕
So if I go ahead and run this through strlen--
strlen-- type in my name.
中文字幕
Hopefully I, indeed, see five.
And there's no notion that you need to care about the backslash zero
中文字幕
in order to terminate the string.
Yeah?
中文字幕
So this upper
No, in fact.
中文字幕
So that's a really good observation.
Let's rewind and actually improve upon this
中文字幕
rather than just translate it from what was our comparable example in C. Let
me go ahead here and actually say, you know what?
中文字幕
S gets s upper.
And then let me just print s, perhaps.
中文字幕
Let's see what happens.
Let me go back here and run Python of capitalize 2.
中文字幕
Enter David.
And it operates on the whole string.
中文字幕
Good intuition.
And honestly, I don't need to do this.
中文字幕
I could just say upper here and really trim this down and do
Python of capitalize, type in my name.
中文字幕
That still works.
And if I really want to be fancy, I don't even need s at all.
中文字幕
I can take this, get rid of that, put this here, immediately call
upper on the user's input and whittle this down to one line, type in David,
中文字幕
and that, too, works.
So you just get lots and lots and lots of more expressiveness.
中文字幕
Good question.
So how do you even know that things like this exist?
中文字幕
Well, quick aside.
Google will truly be your friend in cases like this.
中文字幕
And you'll want to know at this point, there's different versions of Python.
The world is kind of holding out and is still
中文字幕
using, a lot of people, version 2 of Python, which is older by many years
now.
中文字幕
We are using version 3.
And this is where the world is going.
中文字幕
And indeed, Python 2 will be officially deprecated or phased out
in a couple of years, theoretically.
中文字幕
So when you Google, you just want to be mindful of this
so that you don't accidentally make your way to old tutorials, old documentation
中文字幕
and the like.
So let me go ahead and Google Python 3 string, or str, and upper,
中文字幕
just to see if I can get to the documentation.
Here you have a number of tutorials.
中文字幕
But if we focus down here, what you're generally going to want to look for,
at least for the official documentation, is docs.python.org.
中文字幕
You see in the URL it's version 3, and that's where we want to go.
So let me go ahead and click on this, common string operators.
中文字幕
And I will disclaim this--
I think, personally, Python's documentation
中文字幕
is not terribly newbie-friendly.
Like, it's written fairly arcanely and you kind of
中文字幕
have to really dig to understand certain things.
That's fine.
中文字幕
You'll get comfortable with it over time.
But if you're feeling a little overwhelmed by,
中文字幕
oh my God, I just want to know about upper, everyone feels this way too.
So control F or Command F is your friend, upper.
中文字幕
Let me go ahead and search for this.
And it's not actually on this page, is it?
中文字幕
String-- string methods.
Here we go.
中文字幕
String methods.
OK, so under string methods, let me go ahead and search for upper.
中文字幕
And down here, indeed, is the documentation.
So the convention will be the name of the data type in question--
中文字幕
str for string--
the name of the function here.
中文字幕
It would tell you in parentheses if it takes any arguments, but it doesn't.
And so it returns a copy of the string with all of the cased characters
中文字幕
converted to uppercase-- that just means the letters of the alphabet
essentially--
中文字幕
and then some additional documentation, and so forth.
It gets pretty low-level pretty quickly.
中文字幕
These are the equivalent of the man pages.
And there is no CS50 reference for Python.
中文字幕
That was just for C. So just realize that there's
this documentation available.
中文字幕
And you'll notice there's bunches of functions.
Strip is actually kind of a popular one, or L strip or R strip.
中文字幕
If you have whitespace at the beginning or end of a line
because your human got a little sloppy or there's new lines in a file,
中文字幕
you can call strip on a string and get rid of whitespace to the left
and right to kind of clean it up.
中文字幕
Terribly useful for things like data science applications
and analysis of data where you just kind of clean up messy data.
中文字幕
So many functions like that are built in for you.
All right, so let's take a look at a few other examples reminiscent of features
中文字幕
we did have in C, such as this one here.
Suppose I want to write a program that takes
中文字幕
command line arguments, much like resize,
with which we started today's story.
中文字幕
Let's not even use the CS50 library.
Let's do this.
中文字幕
If you want access to argv, recall in C it looked like this-- int,
argc, string, argv.
中文字幕
It looked like this in C.
Well, unfortunately, if you're not using main,
中文字幕
it would be nice if you can still use command line arguments.
And you can, but you have to import them.
中文字幕
It's a library that provides you with access.
From the sys or system library, you can import argv in Python.
中文字幕
And that gives you access to command line arguments as a feature.
Then you can say something like this.
中文字幕
If the length of argv--
which is just an array, recall, in C--
中文字幕
equals equals 2, then go ahead and say hello.
And let's go ahead and print out whatever the user typed in, argv 1.
中文字幕
Else, let's just by default say hello world.
So in English, what's happening?
中文字幕
If the user typed in a command line argument-- say, hello so-and-so.
Else if the human did not type in exactly one command line argument,
中文字幕
just say, by default, hello world.
So let me save this.
中文字幕
Do Python of argv1, or rather zero.
Enter.
中文字幕
OK, I didn't type in a word after the command.
So now let's do it again and I'll type in Brian's name.
中文字幕
Enter, hello Brian.
Let's do it again.
中文字幕
Veronica, enter.
Now, there's something that's not quite the same as C. How many words did I
中文字幕
just type at the prompt?
3.
中文字幕
So that would suggest that this is argv 0, argv 1, and argv 2.
And yet, I'm printing argv 1, not argv 2.
中文字幕
So how do I think about this?
The code is correct, but it's different from C.
中文字幕
What does argv technically store when you run a command like these?
Remember, let's rewind.
中文字幕
In C, argv 0 stored what?
Name of the file.
中文字幕
The name of the file or the name of the program you just ran.
Notice, though, the program I just ran is called Python.
中文字幕
And so you would think that argv 0 would have Python in it,
but it doesn't because notice if I'm printing argv 1,
中文字幕
you would think that's 0, 1.
You would think I just said hello argv 0 .py, But I didn't.
中文字幕
argv 1 clearly prints Veronica or Brian.
So it stands to reason argv 0 is this, which
中文字幕
means this is, like, argv negative 1.
Python is excluded from the argument vector, as it's called.
中文字幕
The command line arguments do not include the name of the interpreter.
But otherwise, it works exactly the same as it did once upon a time.
中文字幕
And notice, too, with this new for construct,
notice what you can do whenever you have access to an array of things.
中文字幕
If I go into argv1.py and import argv again, let me go ahead now
and just-- you know what?
中文字幕
For s in argv, go ahead and print out s.
It's really succinct.
中文字幕
What is this going to do?
Let me go ahead and do Python of argv1, enter.
中文字幕
And it just prints out the name of the file.
If I go ahead and say foo, bar, baz, three random words,
中文字幕
it prints out all of those words.
And so what's powerful about Python is honestly this for loop.
中文字幕
There's no int i, less than, plus plus, any of that.
You just say, give me a variable called s
中文字幕
and iterate over the entirety of the thing on the right, which is presumed,
in this case, to be an array.
中文字幕
You can be even more powerful than that.
If I-- just like in C weeks ago--
中文字幕
look at characters in these strings-- let me do argv2.py--
suppose that this iterate over each string in argv,
中文字幕
and then here iterate over each character in s, I can do for c in s
and now print out the character.
中文字幕
So now when I run this same command but on argv2.py,
notice what's going to happen.
中文字幕
Let me raise this a little bit.
Enter.
中文字幕
It prints every character from every word one at a time.
But it did so this time based on using these two for loops.
中文字幕
So what does this mean?
When you have an array, as we've called it,
中文字幕
you can iterate over everything in the array.
When you have a string, you can iterate over every character in the string.
中文字幕
And this is where Python just gets wonderfully
flexible to do this again and again.
中文字幕
All right, let's take a look at--
let's see-- compared strings already.
中文字幕
We copied strings.
Let's go ahead and do this in Python.
中文字幕
Recall that we ran into a fundamental limitation of C,
and it would seem programming, when we had example called swap
中文字幕
and no swap back in the day where I was just
trying to swap two values, x and y.
中文字幕
And recall that I hardcoded something like x is 1 and y is 2.
And the whole goal was simply to first say, x is such and such,
中文字幕
y is such and such.
Let me go ahead and make that a format string.
中文字幕
Then I wanted to print this again.
But somewhere in here, I wanted to swap x and y.
中文字幕
So to punctuate our sort of exploration of just what Python can do,
if you want to swap two variables, x and y, that's fine, just do it.
中文字幕
And it's this magical shell game that just works in Python.
Now, technically these are what are called tuples on the left.
中文字幕
It's a x comma y pair.
It's latitude comma longitude.
中文字幕
So there's an actual underlying mental model for what's going on here.
But in effect, you're literally switching them
中文字幕
and you don't need the temporary variable.
Python the language takes care of that for you.
中文字幕
All right, let's look at a more powerful feature
still, this time using what's actually called a list.
中文字幕
So a moment ago I was using argv 0, 1, 2, as our examples.
And I was calling them arrays.
中文字幕
They're not arrays anymore.
Python does not have arrays.
中文字幕
Python has lists.
And lists sounds reminiscent of linked lists.
中文字幕
And indeed, they are.
In Python, you have lists that are resizable.
中文字幕
You don't have to decide in advance how big they are or how small they are.
They will just grow and shrink for you just like a linked list will,
中文字幕
but you don't have to write the linked list yourself.
Yeah?
中文字幕
Sure.
Oh, sure.
中文字幕
Let me open that file up in argv1.
This one here?
中文字幕
No, it was, like, .
Oh, this one here.
中文字幕
Yeah.
bracket notation ..
中文字幕
Yes, you can still-- so argv, I called it an array,
but that was a white lie a moment ago.
中文字幕
It's actually a list, a linked list.
But whereas a linked list in C does not allow you to use square brackets,
中文字幕
you have to use a for loop or a while loop
to iterate over the whole thing to find what you're looking for, in Python,
中文字幕
if something is in a list, you can just use, yes, the square brackets
to get at that specific element.
中文字幕
Or I'm saying you could use the f right before--
Oh, I could have, yes.
中文字幕
I didn't use the F, just because frankly it just gets ugly eventually.
But yes, I could have also done this to achieve the exact same effect.
中文字幕
It just starts to look cryptic.
OK, so let's actually introduce a list, which itself is a data type in Python,
中文字幕
as well as in languages like C++ and Java,
if some of you have that background, as well.
中文字幕
So here, in list.py, let me go ahead and do the following.
Let me first import from the CS50 library getInt
中文字幕
so that we can get some ints from the user.
Let me give myself an array, a.k.a.
中文字幕
now a list in Python.
So in C you can't really express quite this idea.
中文字幕
In Python, if you want a variable called numbers
and you want to initialize it to an empty list,
中文字幕
you just literally do open bracket, close bracket.
No number in between them.
中文字幕
And as before, no semi-colon.
Let's now do the following forever until I break out of this.
中文字幕
Let me go ahead and get a number from the user,
just by asking them for some number.
中文字幕
Then let me say, if not number, go ahead and break out of this.
This is going to, as an aside, just let me quit out
中文字幕
of this by hitting Control D as we discussed ever so briefly a while back.
But that's just a UI feature.
中文字幕
So this is what's kind of cool.
Suppose I want to implement the notion of checking
中文字幕
if the number the user's typed in is in the list already, and if so,
not add it.
中文字幕
I'm going to go ahead and do that.
But first, let's just do this--
中文字幕
numbers.append number.
And this is a new feature.
中文字幕
So what do I want to do here?
For number in numbers--
中文字幕
I'll explain this in a second--
let me go ahead and print number.
中文字幕
So what is this program aspiring to do?
At the very top, I'm importing getInt.
中文字幕
At the very top below that, I'm just giving myself an empty array,
now called a list, called numbers.
中文字幕
Then I do the following forever.
Go ahead and get the number from the user.
中文字幕
If he or she did not actually type in a number, just break out of this.
The program is done.
中文字幕
But here's the new feature.
Just as with strings, they are objects, so to speak.
中文字幕
They are data structures that have functions built in.
So do lists have functions built in.
中文字幕
There is literally a function inside of every Python list
called append that literally does that.
中文字幕
You call append and it appends whatever its input
is to whatever the list itself is.
中文字幕
So in C, you might have had to use realloc.
You might have had to add something to the end of the list.
中文字幕
None of that happens anymore.
Just at a high level, you say append this to the list
中文字幕
and let the language take care of it for you.
Then down here, left-aligned all the way at the end,
中文字幕
is just saying, for number in numbers.
Like, iterate over all of the numbers in the list and print out one at a time.
中文字幕
So let's try this.
Let me go down here and do Python of--
中文字幕
this is list.py-- and let me go ahead and type in a number like 13, 42, 50.
And I'm going to hit Control D, which means that's it, I'm done.
中文字幕
And there we see the three numbers.
It looks a little stupid because you know what?
中文字幕
I think I need a print here.
Let's fix this.
中文字幕
Let me rerun this.
13, 42, 50, Control D, there we go.
中文字幕
One per line.
But what this program has is honestly kind of a bug, potentially.
中文字幕
Suppose I want unique numbers, now I have three 13s.
But I'd ideally just want one copy of every number for whatever reason.
中文字幕
I want uniqueness.
Well, notice how easily you can express that.
中文字幕
If my goal is to only conditionally add a number to the numbers list
if it's not already there, how would you do this in C?
中文字幕
You have an array called numbers and you want to first check
is a number in that array.
中文字幕
What would you do in English?
A for loop.
中文字幕
A for loop, right?
You'd probably start at the left, iterate over
中文字幕
the whole array looking for the number and then conclude true or false,
it's in there.
中文字幕
It's not hard but it's a little annoying.
You have to write more code, a couple of lines, four lines for a for loop.
中文字幕
In Python, just say what you mean.
If number not in numbers, append it.
中文字幕
And it reads much more like English.
At the end of the day, some human wrote the for loop that does that operation.
中文字幕
But we, the more modern programmers, can just now say, if number not in numbers,
append it.
中文字幕
And so it is meant to read more English-like.
So let's try this now.
中文字幕
13, 13, 50, done.
Now I just get one copy of the 13 because it's checking that for me.
中文字幕
Now, running time is still an issue.
Consider this, theoretically, you're still
中文字幕
wasting some time looking for a number because someone wrote
code that's probably linear search.
中文字幕
Maybe it's binary search if it's sorted.
But someone wrote that code.
中文字幕
But the point is, with these higher level languages,
these more modern languages like Python, that is not our problem, necessarily.
中文字幕
It only becomes our problem if the program is just
too slow for some reason and we really need to get into the weeds of why.
中文字幕
All right, let's look at a final feature syntactically
before we try this to a more generalized problem.
中文字幕
Let me go ahead and save a file called struct0.py,
which is reminiscent of struct0.c a few weeks back.
中文字幕
And let me go ahead and from the CS50 library import getString.
Let me go ahead and give myself an array this time called students that's empty,
中文字幕
or a list called students.
And then let me just get three students for the sake of discussion.
中文字幕
So for i in range 3, that just iterates three times,
let me go ahead and ask the user for their name.
中文字幕
So getString, ask them for their name.
Then let me go ahead and ask them for their dorm
中文字幕
and go ahead and get string for dorm.
And then that's enough.
中文字幕
Let me now go ahead and append the student to my list.
So students dot append.
中文字幕
But I don't really have a student structure yet.
Now, there's many ways we can solve this, but let
中文字幕
me propose the simplest one.
It turns out in Python you can declare hash tables so wonderfully simply.
中文字幕
A hash table is just a collection of key value pairs.
And I would argue at this point in my example I have keys and values.
中文字幕
I have a name which is a key and the value, like David or whatever,
another key called dorm, and then a value which is like Matthews
中文字幕
or wherever.
And so keys and values.
中文字幕
So it would be kind of nice if I could create for myself a hash table--
or even a try, for that matter-- that allows me to store this data.
中文字幕
Well, it turns out in Python, I can do just that.
I can go ahead and create an object called student
中文字幕
using curly bracket notation.
And you can literally do this.
中文字幕
The name shall be one key.
And now it's going to take on that value.
中文字幕
Dorm shall be another key and it's going to take on that value.
So I could call this anything I want-- x and y
中文字幕
and have the values David and Matthews or whatever it is I'm going to type in.
But if you want a very generalized data structure
中文字幕
that isn't just a list of values from left to right, but has metadata--
a key, or if you think of a spreadsheet, a column name
中文字幕
called name and a column name called dorm, each of which has values--
you just use curly braces.
中文字幕
And you put the keys in quotes and then a colon.
And then if you've got multiple keys, you just put a comma.
中文字幕
So it's a little cryptic, but this is just like a container, a hash table,
that contains words and values.
中文字幕
Now, in p set 4, when you implemented speller,
you actually just said yes or no, is the word in the dictionary?
中文字幕
But you certainly could have stored more information
instead of just Boolean values.
中文字幕
You just tended to not need to do that.
So what does this mean for me?
中文字幕
At this point in the story, I have an object,
as it's called in Python, that stores these keys and these values.
中文字幕
So if later on I want to iterate over them, I can do this.
For student in-- oh, you have to append it--
中文字幕
so student.append student.
Let's add the student to the list.
中文字幕
So for student in students, which is just how
you iterate over every one of the things in that list.
中文字幕
Let me just go ahead and say a sentence like, I want to say so and so
is in this dorm.
中文字幕
So how do express that?
Well, so and so, I need to get access to the student's name.
中文字幕
And the way I can do this is as follows.
I could say, let's go ahead and say curly brace student bracket
中文字幕
name close bracket.
And then here, I can go ahead and say--
中文字幕
oops, let me put quotes in here--
and then here I can say student bracket quote unquote dorm.
中文字幕
So this is admittedly the most cryptic example we've done thus far.
But let's tease it apart as a format string.
中文字幕
So if I zoom in on this, what am I doing?
The curly braces and the f just means format this string.
中文字幕
So you can ignore the curly braces as part of our story from earlier.
Student is the name of the variable in the for loop.
中文字幕
So it's the current student.
The square brackets are new.
中文字幕
In C, the only time we used square brackets was in what context?
Arrays.
中文字幕
And what did we always put in those square brackets?
A number.
中文字幕
Yeah, so 0, 1, 2.
You can index into an array.
中文字幕
What's cool about an object--
or a hash table more generally, as we're now defining it--
中文字幕
is you can index into the variable using not numbers, but words.
So you could think of student as being like a list or an array
中文字幕
with two values-- name and dorm.
But it's nice to be able to refer to those not as zero and one
中文字幕
or some stupid arbitrary number, but rather by keys--
name and dorm.
中文字幕
So this syntax here, though cryptic, says go inside the student
object and get me the value of the key called name.
中文字幕
And this says the same thing about dorm.
So an object in Python--
中文字幕
or more generally a hash table-- allows you to associate keys with values.
And this is quite simply the syntax you use for that.
中文字幕
So let me go ahead and run this.
Struct0.py, type in my name.
中文字幕
Let's say Matthews.
Let's do, like, Veronica, Weld.
中文字幕
Let's do Brian.
Brian, where did you live?
中文字幕
Which year?
Freshman year.
中文字幕
Pennypacker.
Pennypacker, enter.
中文字幕
Not that these specifics really matter, but now we
have expressed all of these sentences.
中文字幕
So the short of it now is we didn't quite see this in C,
but we did see a hint of this when we implemented our own hash
中文字幕
table in C so that we can actually access keys and values arbitrarily.
So let's do a-- actually, let me pause here for any questions
中文字幕
before we bring back Mario.
All right.
中文字幕
So let's now not just do examples for the sake of demonstration,
but rewind to an old friend that we've seen a few times
中文字幕
and just look at a few different screens.
So in Super Mario Bros, running left to right
中文字幕
you might recall or have seen that there's stuff like this in the sky.
And Mario's supposed to run under it and jump up
中文字幕
and he gets coins or whatever by jumping up and hitting these question marks.
So this is mostly a very contrived way of saying,
中文字幕
suppose we want to print out four question
marks on the screen just like Super Mario Bros, how could we do it?
中文字幕
It's going to be a little black and white, a little textual,
but how do I print out four question marks?
中文字幕
Well, let me go over here and let me create a file called,
let's say, Mario0.py.
中文字幕
And how do I do this?
What's the simplest way to do this, print four question marks?
中文字幕
OK, I heard print.
OK, four question marks.
中文字幕
Very good.
So let's go ahead and run Mario0.
中文字幕
Correct, that's right.
So this is not bad.
中文字幕
It's one string, not a huge deal.
Let's do it at least with a loop, as we've been often doing,
中文字幕
just to improve the design, even though this
is a very tiny, tiny, tiny example.
中文字幕
So Mario1.py, let's go ahead and print this out with a loop, for instance.
So how do I do this?
中文字幕
How do I print four question marks, but one at a time?
For i in range four, print, question mark.
中文字幕
Save, all right.
So Python, Mario.
中文字幕
Does anyone want to yell out, no, don't do that?
OK, thanks.
中文字幕
That's great.
All right, so why did you not want me to do that?
中文字幕
Because they're all vertical.
So we did have a fix for this how.
中文字幕
Do I tell print, don't end your lines with the default new line?
So and equals just quote unquote to override the default backslash n value.
中文字幕
So now I can rerun this.
All right, it's a little buggy.
中文字幕
So how can I fix this and only put a newline after the last one?
Yeah, honestly, just do print nothing.
中文字幕
And that will have the effect of printing a new line for free.
So let's do this.
中文字幕
OK.
Now we've got a good example there.
中文字幕
All right, so it turns out we actually printed along the way
a separate example, which looked like this, albeit with four blocks.
中文字幕
So we won't-- let's go ahead and do this now vertically,
not with question marks, but with hashes like bricks.
中文字幕
So if we want to print out those three hashes,
allow me to draw some inspiration from this and let's say in Mario2.py,
中文字幕
let me go ahead and just say for i in range of three,
go ahead and print out just one block.
中文字幕
And as you've been advising, just do this--
or rather, no, let's use the default to print out
中文字幕
a vertical bar of three blocks.
So this is Mario2.py.
中文字幕
And now we've done something reminiscent of that.
But now things get a little interesting if we go underground.
中文字幕
And let's focus on this square.
So three by three, for instance, because we've not quite
中文字幕
seen something like this.
So in our last example here, let's see.
中文字幕
Could we get maybe a brave volunteer to come on up, tie some of these ideas
together?
中文字幕
Is that a hand back there?
Come on down.
中文字幕
So this will be Mario3.py, the goal of which is to print a brick,
a bigger brick--
中文字幕
it's like 3 by 3-- hello again.
ANDREA: Hello.
中文字幕
For the audience, what's your name?
ANDREA: Andrea.
中文字幕
Andrea, nice to see you.
ANDREA: Nice to see you.
中文字幕
All right, so the goal at hand
is to print a three by three grid of just
中文字幕
hashes reminiscent of those bricks.
All right, you're in charge.
中文字幕
ANDREA: All right.
Should I do, like, a loop or something?
中文字幕
Whatever gets the job done.
All right, for.
中文字幕
OK, good.
OK, interesting.
中文字幕
OK, print, quote unquote, print, yeah, OK.
ANDREA: OK.
中文字幕
Oh, right.
Key detail.
中文字幕
ANDREA: What was it, a hash?
A hash is fine, yeah.
中文字幕
ANDREA: OK.
All right.
中文字幕
And before we do this, does everyone want her to run this program
and be correct?
中文字幕
Don't do it.
No, why?
中文字幕
Someone who claims no, what?
What's your concern?
中文字幕
N equals-- it'll do it
Good, OK.
中文字幕
So you fixed that.
Good.
中文字幕
Any other concerns?
Yeah?
中文字幕
OK.
Is it going to go up and down?
中文字幕
Well, let's see.
Can you walk us through verbally-- do we have--
中文字幕
can you walk us through what the program does?
ANDREA: For i in range 3, so this will happen three times, then j
中文字幕
in range three, the next thing will also happen three times.
So we print a hash.
中文字幕
And then we another hash and another hash
because the end is the quotation marks.
中文字幕
OK.
ANDREA: And then that happens and then we print a new line.
中文字幕
And then it should execute that three times.
All right.
中文字幕
What do you think?
Do you-- the duck is convinced.
中文字幕
All right, why don't you go ahead and save the file.
Let's try.
中文字幕
No harm in trying, so right or wrong, let's see.
This is called Mario3.py, and I think we have round of applause if we could.
中文字幕
Very nicely done.
All right.
中文字幕
So let's-- and if you'd like one more.
So let's take a look at one final example,
中文字幕
coming full circle from where we began.
We of course looked at resize.
中文字幕
And let's open that up, just to see how I got away with writing so little code
and actually getting that job done.
中文字幕
So in resize.py, which is where we began,
notice that I had a few lines that hopefully look a little more familiar
中文字幕
now.
But we didn't exactly introduce all of these features ourselves.
中文字幕
So it turns out in line one and line two we have
one unfamiliar and one familiar line.
中文字幕
Line two just gives us access to a command line arguments, which
we needed for resizing the bitmap.
中文字幕
Line one is where a lot of the power is coming from.
It turns out there's a library in Python called pillow
中文字幕
that you can install by typing a certain command at your terminal.
It doesn't necessarily come with your Mac or PC.
中文字幕
You have to download it and install it with a command.
And then if you read its documentation, it
中文字幕
will say, from pill for pillow import image.
Now, that's not a specific image.
中文字幕
That's the name of a library called the image
library that comes with that software that someone freely made available.
中文字幕
So that's just saying, give me access to an image-related library.
And undoubtedly, there could exist similar things in C. But we of course
中文字幕
did things very hands-on low-level.
All right, if the length of argv is not 4, yell at the user with the usage.
中文字幕
And that's just if they don't cooperate by typing in as they should, this.
It's a little more verbose now because we have Python
中文字幕
and we have the file extension.
But we could technically clean that up if we really wanted.
中文字幕
Lines 7, 8, and 9, there's nothing really new there.
I'm just declaring three variables implicitly typed.
中文字幕
I don't have to bother saying int or string.
I'm accessing argv 1, 2, and 3, which is 1, 2, and 3.
中文字幕
And then I'm doing one thing line 7.
What is line 7 doing that's important?
中文字幕
I'm changing the argument from what is technically
a string by default-- because indeed, it came from the human hands
中文字幕
at a keyboard-- and converting it into a number.
Now, as an aside, if the user does not provide a number like 2 or 10,
中文字幕
this code could break.
To be fair, I should really have some error checking
中文字幕
to make sure if the user typed in hello and not 2 or 10,
I need to catch that error.
中文字幕
So I'm being a little sloppy.
But it was really meant to demonstrate succinct code.
中文字幕
So now we have infile and outfile defined exactly as before.
So we have just three lines left that actually implement most of the magic.
中文字幕
Yeah.
Wait, say the last part again.
中文字幕
Yes.
There was almost
中文字幕
Good observation.
So this is not just converting the user's input to the equivalent ASCII
中文字幕
value because that's not what we want.
This int used here is actually converting it
中文字幕
as via a2i, a function that you've probably used a couple of weeks ago,
it's just named a little more succinctly.
中文字幕
There is a function via which you could convert a character or a string
to its ASCII equivalent.
中文字幕
But that's not what's going on here.
It does the more intuitive turn this into an integer
中文字幕
without using a cryptically named function like a2i.
So let's scroll down just a little further to these last few lines
中文字幕
and see what's going on.
Some of them you would only know how to do from having
中文字幕
read the documentation just as we did.
This says give me a variable called in image.
中文字幕
Could have called it anything.
I'm just trying to be consistent with in file.
中文字幕
This says, use the image library.
Use its open function that comes with it.
中文字幕
So image is some kind of structure, inside of which
is some useful image-related functionality.
中文字幕
So call its open function on the name of the file,
then go ahead and extract its height and width.
中文字幕
So turns out this is another tuple, if you will.
Tuples, again, are like x comma y, latitude comma longitude.
中文字幕
You'd only know that it is a tuple from the documentation.
So when I say width comma height, this is taking what's technically a list
中文字幕
of size two-- or really, a tuple--
and it's just extracting for me the width and the height.
中文字幕
But let me wave my hands at that particular syntax.
The rest of this just says the following.
中文字幕
Give me a new variable called out image.
Call the input image's resize function, another piece of functionality
中文字幕
built into it, just like open, and change it
by this width and this height-- the original width times n,
中文字幕
the original height times n.
No padding manipulation, that's all the responsibility of the library.
中文字幕
Some other human dealt with all of that for us.
And this last line, perhaps not surprisingly,
中文字幕
saves the output image to that file name.
So in just, what, 15 lines of code and fewer
中文字幕
if we get rid of some of the whitespace can you
implement the entirety of resize.
中文字幕
But really focusing on the logic of the problem,
I want to take an input from the user.
中文字幕
I want to scale it up by a factor of n.
And I want to save out the file.
中文字幕
That's what you care about.
You don't necessarily care about getting into the weeds of exactly what it
中文字幕
was you had to do when you did it in C.
So let's do one final example here.
中文字幕
You'll recall from problem set four you implemented your own spell checker.
And odds are you did a try or a hash table or the like.
中文字幕
And it turns out that is non-trivial, certainly in C.
And it's non-trivial certainly for the first time in any language.
中文字幕
But let me take a stab at doing this now in Python.
Let me go into source 6 where I have a speller example.
中文字幕
And notice that in this folder today I've brought a few files with me.
So I've brought a copy of the dictionaries
中文字幕
from p set four, a copy of the text files, like la-la land and the like
in text.
中文字幕
And then I brought two files-- dictionary.py and speller.py--
the latter of which is an implementation of speller.c in Python.
中文字幕
And I'm not going to pull that one up because we wrote that one entirely
for you.
中文字幕
But let me go ahead and write, for instance, just my own dictionary.
So dictionary.py is the analog of dictionary.c.
中文字幕
And let's go ahead and set this up.
Let me go ahead and create this file in a separate folder
中文字幕
for now, so dictionary.py.
And there's a few functions in dictionary.c
中文字幕
which we should probably get around to implementing.
What are those functions?
中文字幕
Load.
Load was one, and load takes
中文字幕
the name of a file or a dictionary.
So let's do this.
中文字幕
And I'll just say to do.
Come back to that.
中文字幕
What other functions were in dictionary.c?
Check, so def check.
中文字幕
And what did check take as an input?
A word, yep.
中文字幕
So we'll come back to this and just come back to that to do.
What other functions?
中文字幕
Size.
Size was one, so def size.
中文字幕
This did not take input, but it just returned the size of the structure.
So we'll come back to that.
中文字幕
And lastly?
Unload.
中文字幕
OK, so unload.
All right, so this is the Python version of the distribution code
中文字幕
for speller for your dictionary file.
So unload also didn't take an argument.
中文字幕
So that's something for us to do, too.
So what's the gist of making a spell checker?
中文字幕
You are loading words in your load function from a dictionary file.
And the goal is to load those somehow into memory.
中文字幕
You had a design decision for the p set in C,
where you could make a hash table or a try
中文字幕
or even a linked list or even an array.
But odds are the first of those two were probably more efficient.
中文字幕
So it turns out that in Python, you have the ability
to store words pretty readily in any number of data structures.
中文字幕
You have not just ints and floats and strings,
but you clearly have lists, as we've seen.
中文字幕
We call them objects or hashes, hash tables.
And there's other things, too, even called
中文字幕
sets, where a set is kind of just a collection of words
which would be very nicely searchable.
中文字幕
And so you know what?
If I want to ultimately load some words, let
中文字幕
me give myself a global variable called words
and just initialize it to an empty set.
中文字幕
So I have a global variable called words and nothing is in it just yet.
But it's a set of words.
中文字幕
How do I go about loading words into that dictionary?
Well, let's go ahead and implement load here.
中文字幕
So let me go ahead and declare a variable called file and open
this dictionary in read mode, just as in C.
中文字幕
And then how do I integrate over the lines in a file?
We've not seen that.
中文字幕
But I do know how to iterate over the strings in an array
and the characters in a string.
中文字幕
So let me go with my instinct for line in file.
Indeed, this will do exactly what you want it to do.
中文字幕
Then let me go ahead and add to my words data structure the following line.
And then let me close the file.
中文字幕
And then let me just say return true because all is well.
Done.
中文字幕
All right, so I'm cutting a few corners, technically.
Let me use that function I alluded to earlier.
中文字幕
Let me go ahead and call r strip and strip off
the new line because in the file, technically,
中文字幕
when you're reading in those words, every line ends with a backslash zero.
That's now part of the word.
中文字幕
So a minor correction there that I'm stripping off the line.
But that's it for load.
中文字幕
How do I now check if a given word is in that set?
Well, I can just say, if word in words return true.
中文字幕
Else, return false.
Done with check.
中文字幕
How do I return the size of this data structure?
How about I just return the length of that structure, words, and then
中文字幕
unload--
heck, Python's doing this all for me--
中文字幕
done.
Let me shrink this.
中文字幕
And you know what?
This is a little verbose.
中文字幕
I don't actually need to do this if else.
I could just return word in words and that will return a Boolean for me.
中文字幕
And honestly, if I want to lower case it, that's easy.
I can just do this and take care of that.
中文字幕
Now it's even better.
That's p set 4.
中文字幕
Excited?
Wish we had done this in C?
中文字幕
So what is the whole point of all of this,
because the goal wasn't to create sort of great angst and wonder now.
中文字幕
But the whole point of having introduced C over these past few weeks is to,
one, none of this now do you take for granted.
中文字幕
I mean, you might be longing for having implemented this in Python.
And you might have had to read some documentation
中文字幕
and figure out the various syntax.
But my God.
中文字幕
We whittled down what probably took most of you hours into just seconds
once you're more comfortable with the language.
中文字幕
But also, to our very earliest point today,
once you have the right language and the right tool for the job.
中文字幕
Now, it's not to say that this is perfect, because in fact,
let's go ahead and do some tests.
中文字幕
Let me go into my terminal window here.
And I actually brought my own solution in my C folder here.
中文字幕
Let's see.
I have my own code to speller implemented in C here.
中文字幕
And let me go ahead and run a test.
Let me go ahead and run speller on, say, the text Shakespeare.
中文字幕
That's a pretty big input.
Let's go ahead and hit Enter.
中文字幕
And this is my spell checker running.
And all the words are outputting.
中文字幕
And the time total to run speller in C was, say, 0.9 seconds.
So that's actually pretty good.
中文字幕
In a second window, let me go up here in another terminal window.
And let me go into today's code and into the speller folder where I have
中文字幕
a Python version that I'm going to run as follows-- speller.py--
let me go ahead and run it on Shakespeare.
中文字幕
So we've not looked at speller.py.
But it is essentially line for line a port, a translation, from C to Python.
中文字幕
But you're welcome to look at that online.
And it's using my dictionary.py file.
中文字幕
Let me go ahead and run that.
It's running through all the words.
中文字幕
Top is Python, bottom is C. Here we go.
Here we go.
中文字幕
Now, this is a bit misleading because again, the internet is the way.
We're using a web-based IDE, and so it's funny that that appears so many times.
中文字幕
And you'll see it's not 10, 20 seconds, however long that was.
That was just the internet being slow.
中文字幕
And all we're timing is your functions in both C and Python.
But what's the takeaway between Python and C?
中文字幕
Same inputs.
What do you see?
中文字幕
Yeah?
Be more concise .
中文字幕
Yeah, I wouldn't say concise.
That's more aesthetic.
中文字幕
It's more--
Specific .
中文字幕
Well, not even that, I think.
These are correct.
中文字幕
Both of them are correct.
All the important numbers at the top are identical.
中文字幕
But what is clearly different, though?
It's slower.
中文字幕
So Python seems to be slower, right?
It takes in total-- if we just look at two numbers--
中文字幕
1.55 seconds in Python, if you ignore the internet speed
and just look at the code performance, versus 0.9.
中文字幕
So it's almost twice as slow as C. So what's the takeaway there?
Well, yes, it took me, what, 10, 20, 30 seconds to write the code.
中文字幕
But it's taking me twice as long to run it.
Now, not a big deal, of course, when we're
中文字幕
talking a few seconds here and there.
But if this were a big data set that you're analyzing for some project
中文字幕
or for work or for any kind of analysis project and the data is much larger
than even this-- especially in the medical field or the like--
中文字幕
maybe you don't want to use Python.
Sure, you can bang out the code in just a few minutes, maybe a few hours.
中文字幕
But once you run it, damn, it's slower than using something like C.
Whereas in C, might take you more time upfront.
中文字幕
And you might not even have the comfort with C
anymore so it's going to take an even longer because you have to go relearn
中文字幕
the language.
But when you run it, wow, it runs twice as fast.
中文字幕
You therefore need less RAM, potentially,
less hardware or less expensive hardware because you can get away with more.
中文字幕
So again, this theme we keep seeing in data structures and algorithms
is trade-offs.
中文字幕
Like, developer time is a resource and it is wonderful that I
and now you would be able to write code so much more quickly.
中文字幕
But you do have to pay a price somewhere.
And there's clearly a price with Python.
中文字幕
And it's not because Python is poorly implemented.
But what is the fundamental difference between the paradigm
中文字幕
of programming in C versus in Python as we've seen it today?
What's different?
中文字幕
Yeah?
line by line, whereas C, it essentially--
中文字幕
optimize running it, it will run ..
Indeed.
中文字幕
And let me flip it around.
So with C, you're compiling down to zeros and ones.
中文字幕
And that compiler is super smart.
And it's going to move things around in memory.
中文字幕
It's going to talk the computer's native language of zeros and ones.
Python is, indeed, reading your code, by contrast, line by line, top to bottom,
中文字幕
left to right.
And even though technically underneath the hood there is a compilation step,
中文字幕
there is nonetheless some overhead involved.
The mere fact that we're no longer running clang and then
中文字幕
getting 0's and 1's or running make and getting zeros and ones, that's great.
But we have to pay the price somewhere.
中文字幕
So this is going to be thematic.
Like, there is no holy grail among languages or tools or techniques.
中文字幕
There's going to be trade-offs among your comfort, your familiarity
or recollection of a language, how easy it is to use,
中文字幕
how succinctly you can type it, and then how efficiently you can actually
run it on the screen.
中文字幕
And with C, hopefully now-- we will not write any more C-code--
you have an appreciation in Python of when you create a hash--
中文字幕
or a list, rather--
or if you create a set or a hash table or the like, what you're really
中文字幕
getting access to is someone else's implementation of p
set four and p set three and p set two and p set one, in some form,
中文字幕
but now exposed to you in a more powerful and more modern language.
So let's end there officially today.
中文字幕
And next week, we'll do the same thing, but in the context of web programming.